<?xml version="1.0"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Nate Eagle - Posts and Bits (old feed)</title><link href="http://nateeagle.com/"/><link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="http://nateeagle.com/atom.xml"/><updated>Invalid Date</updated><id>http://nateeagle.com/</id><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><email>nate@nateeagle.com</email><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/upholstery-a-css3-pattern</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/upholstery-a-css3-pattern"/><title>Upholstery: a CSS3 Pattern</title><updated>Tue Aug 30 2011 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;By now, you&amp;#39;ve seen &lt;a href=&quot;leaverou.me/css3patterns/&quot;&gt;Lea Verou&amp;#39;s CSS3 Patterns Gallery&lt;/a&gt;. I really dug it when I saw it a few months ago. There are some nice patterns in there (&amp;quot;carbon&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://leaverou.me/css3patterns/#carbon&quot;&gt;http://leaverou.me/css3patterns/#carbon&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &amp;quot;Japanese cube&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://leaverou.me/css3patterns/#japanese-cube&quot;&gt;http://leaverou.me/css3patterns/#japanese-cube&lt;/a&gt; are my favorites) and I love generating graphics with code. CSS gradient syntax made my brain hurt, though, and the first time I tried creating a pattern of my own, I wasn&amp;#39;t very successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I used CSS gradients, I tended to &amp;quot;generate&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.colorzilla.com/gradient-editor/&quot;&gt;http://www.colorzilla.com/gradient-editor/&lt;/a&gt; them. That worked okay, but the problem with a tool like that is that it can leave you forever dependent on UI elements and tedious fiddling to get the effect you want. CSS syntax shouldn&amp;#39;t be so difficult that it requires a separate tool: the syntax is just a tool itself, after all, intended to make it easy to work with browser code more complicated than anything I&amp;#39;ll ever write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So: we&amp;#39;ve started up a new tradition at AOL for front-end developers called the FED Challenge. It&amp;#39;s a biweekly contest that&amp;#39;s supposed to encourage developers to try out new techniques and technologies they might not already know about, or to try their hand at something they&amp;#39;re less familiar with. I decided to make the second FED challenge creating a CSS3 Pattern ala the examples in Verou&amp;#39;s gallery, which gave me a chance to finally get past my gradient brain pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m happy to report that it didn&amp;#39;t take very long. Luckily for all of us, Webkit has &amp;quot;changed its gradient syntax&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webkit.org/blog/1424/css3-gradients/&quot;&gt;http://www.webkit.org/blog/1424/css3-gradients/&lt;/a&gt; to match Mozilla&amp;#39;s (clearly superior) syntax. And once I got an example in place in jsFiddle and started to play for a sustained amount of time, all the properties seemed to sort themselves out. (Play is, of course, one of the very best ways to internalize something you don&amp;#39;t know.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, here&amp;#39;s my submission:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 630px&quot; src=&quot;http://jsfiddle.net/nate/37rxC/embedded/result,css,html,js&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was messing around with radial gradients and got the idea that they could be used to create the puffiness of upholstery as well as the shadowed dimples of the buttons. I think it turned out pretty nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the CSS in the tab up above for a highly-formatted, commented version of the CSS, which I find helpful when trying to look through someone else&amp;#39;s styles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you prefer, however, here is the simplest, streamlined, non-vendor-prefixed version of the CSS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{% highlight css %}
background:
radial-gradient(hsl(0, 100%, 27%) 4%, hsl(0, 100%, 18%) 9%, hsla(0, 100%, 20%, 0) 9%) 0 0,
radial-gradient(hsl(0, 100%, 27%) 4%, hsl(0, 100%, 18%) 8%, hsla(0, 100%, 20%, 0) 10%) 50px 50px,
radial-gradient(hsla(0, 100%, 30%, 0.8) 20%, hsla(0, 100%, 20%, 0)) 50px 0,
radial-gradient(hsla(0, 100%, 30%, 0.8) 20%, hsla(0, 100%, 20%, 0)) 0 50px,
radial-gradient(hsla(0, 100%, 20%, 1) 35%, hsla(0, 100%, 20%, 0) 60%) 50px 0,
radial-gradient(hsla(0, 100%, 20%, 1) 35%, hsla(0, 100%, 20%, 0) 60%) 100px 50px,
radial-gradient(hsla(0, 100%, 15%, 0.7), hsla(0, 100%, 20%, 0)) 0 0,
radial-gradient(hsla(0, 100%, 15%, 0.7), hsla(0, 100%, 20%, 0)) 50px 50px,
linear-gradient(45deg, hsla(0, 100%, 20%, 0) 49%, hsla(0, 100%, 0%, 1) 50%, hsla(0, 100%, 20%, 0) 70%) 0 0,
linear-gradient(-45deg, hsla(0, 100%, 20%, 0) 49%, hsla(0, 100%, 0%, 1) 50%, hsla(0, 100%, 20%, 0) 70%) 0 0;
background-color: #300;
background-size: 100px 100px;
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to submit the example to Verou after the contest, and she was kind enough to &amp;quot;add it to the gallery&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://leaverou.me/css3patterns/#upholstery&quot;&gt;http://leaverou.me/css3patterns/#upholstery&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/how-to-output-curly-brackets-in-jekyll</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/how-to-output-curly-brackets-in-jekyll"/><title>How to output curly brackets in Jekyll</title><updated>Wed Aug 31 2011 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s the little things that trip you up, right? Turns out it&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;not super easy&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/3330979/outputting-literal-curly-braces-in-liquid-templates&quot;&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/3330979/outputting-literal-curly-braces-in-liquid-templates&lt;/a&gt; to just output curly brackets / braces in combination with % symbols in Jekyll, which uses Liquid templates, for the not-crazy reason that these are used for its templating language. But if you want to use them for code examples, there&amp;#39;s not really a straightforward way of using escape characters to let you output code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The example I linked to above suggests assigning your code example to a liquid variable, which is an okay solution, but a pain in neck. I came up with an alternative that works a bit better for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of version 0.5.2, Jekyll &amp;quot;lets you set arbitrary configuration variables&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Template-Data&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Template-Data&lt;/a&gt; in your @_config.yml@ that you can then access via @site.whatever@.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I added:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bc.. lcb: &amp;quot;{&amp;quot;
rcb: &amp;quot;}&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p. ...to my @_config.yml@. The variable names stand for left curly bracket and right curly bracket, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I need to use curly brackets in code examples, I just use those variables:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bc.. {{ site.lcb }}{ site.lcb }{{ site.rcb }}% foo | bar %{{ site.lcb }}{ site.lcb }{{ site.rcb }}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p. Which will output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bc.. {{ site.lcb }}% foo | bar %{{ site.rcb }}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p. Still not the greatest solution, but it made my life a lot easier.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/jekyll-not-parsing-includes</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/jekyll-not-parsing-includes"/><title>Jekyll not parsing includes?</title><updated>Wed Aug 31 2011 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This blog is hosted on GitHub and powered by &amp;quot;Jekyll&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, a &amp;quot;blog-aware, static site generator in Ruby&amp;quot; that GitHub uses. Think of it as a way to build a blog that allows for some dynamic templating but is entirely driven by files. Quick tangent: if you build sites for a living but find yourself kind of exhausted with big, feature-rich CMSs by the time you come home, Jekyll just might be what it takes to make blogging for yourself fun again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the main point: Jekyll&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;documentation boldly proclaims this&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/liquid-extensions&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/liquid-extensions&lt;/a&gt; about its includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bq.. If you have small page fragments that you wish to include in multiple places on your site, you can use the @include@ tag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@{{ site.lcb }}% include sig.textile %{{ site.rcb }}@&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jekyll expects all include files to be placed in an @_includes@ directory at the root of your source dir. So this will embed the contents of @/path/to/proto/site/_includes/sig.textile@ into the calling file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p. This might lead you to believe that Jekyll will parse Textile formatting in your included file (or Markdown formatting, for you infidels). &lt;em&gt;But you would be mistaken&lt;/em&gt;. Jekyll will do no such thing: it will blithely output anything you toss into that optimistically named @.textile@ or @.markdown@ file as unparsed text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like I&amp;#39;m not the only one with this problem: &amp;quot;one&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/jekyll-rb/browse_thread/thread/216db15546e79073&quot;&gt;http://groups.google.com/group/jekyll-rb/browse_thread/thread/216db15546e79073&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;quot;two&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/issues/164&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/issues/164&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the moment, the only solution is to abandon our futile dreams of parsed includes and use straight html. But let&amp;#39;s see if we can at least get the documentation changed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/my-first-compass-mixin-text-3d</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/my-first-compass-mixin-text-3d"/><title>My First Compass Mixin: Text-3d</title><updated>Fri Sep 09 2011 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I started using &amp;quot;Compass&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://compass-style.org/&quot;&gt;http://compass-style.org/&lt;/a&gt; because &amp;quot;Chris Eppstein&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/#!/chriseppstein&quot;&gt;http://twitter.com/#!/chriseppstein&lt;/a&gt; himself told me via a tweet that I should check it out. (I mentioned SASS in a tweet, and Mr. Eppstein seems to be as dedicated a promoter as he is talented a developer.) Compass is pretty fantastic, though I will menition that it&amp;#39;s not trivially easy to learn how to use effectively: I&amp;#39;m still working on learning a lot of the ins and outs of using SASS and mixins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;#39;t get too much into Compass itself - part of the idea of this blog is to keep things short and simple - but my favorite part of Compass is the mixins. These work like functions in JavaScript that let you pass in a minimal number of inputs and get out some more complex CSS as a result. This is great for simplifying CSS3, especially, which often requires outputing essentially the same information with the various vendor prefixes. Compass comes with a whole slew of them, but you can also define your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While working on the design for this blog, I found myself using (as I often do) a small trick that uses multiple text shadows to create a 3d text effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!/images/posts/desandro-made-this.png(David DeSandro Made This)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technique was created, as far as I know, by &amp;quot;Dave DeSandro&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://desandro.com/&quot;&gt;http://desandro.com/&lt;/a&gt;, one of the classiest folks in interaction design, who uses it prominently on his homepage. Regardless of its ultimate origin, that&amp;rsquo;s where I picked it up. It creates the illusion of blocky three-dimensional letters that have a side in shadows that stretches back in space. The CSS for it is easy to understand: it just uses the fact that the @text-shadow@ property can have multiple, comma-separated backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{% highlight css %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#mytext {
    text-shadow:
        1px 1px 0 #000,
        2px 2px 0 #000,
        3px 3px 0 #000,
        4px 4px 0 #000,
        5px 5px 0 #000;
    }
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p. The shadow is made up of 1px layers, each offset slightly from the one that preceded it. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example that should make that obvious. (Note: example will not work in browsers that do not support @text-shadow@.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;h3.example1 { color: white; font-family: Futura, Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 48px; font-weight: bold; text-shadow: 1px 1px gray, 2px 2px white, 3px 3px gray, 4px 4px white, 5px 5px gray; text-transform: uppercase; }&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;example1&quot;&gt;Nate Eagle Made This&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% highlight css %}
h3.example1 {
    text-shadow:
        1px 1px gray,
        2px 2px white,
        3px 3px gray,
        4px 4px white,
        5px 5px gray;
    }
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p. I alternated the shadows between gray and white: you can see clearly how they stack. But if you make them a single color:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;h3.example2 { color: white; font-family: Futura, Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 48px; font-weight: bold; text-shadow: 1px 1px gray, 2px 2px gray, 3px 3px gray, 4px 4px gray, 5px 5px gray; text-transform: uppercase; }&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;example2&quot;&gt;Nate Eagle Made This&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% highlight css %}
h3.example2 {
    text-shadow:
        1px 1px gray,
        2px 2px gray,
        3px 3px gray,
        4px 4px gray,
        5px 5px gray;
    }
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p. &amp;hellip;it creates the illusion of a solid side, receding in space. Lovely, yeah? Only problem: it&amp;#39;s kind of a complex declaration. And fiddling around with the color and size of the effect is annoyingly complex: you have to add and remove whole lines, change multiple numbers, change the name of the color multiple times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the perfect candidate for a mixin. Here&amp;rsquo;s &amp;quot;the documentation for defining a mixin&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/docs/yardoc/file.SASS_REFERENCE.html#defining_a_mixin&quot;&gt;http://sass-lang.com/docs/yardoc/file.SASS_REFERENCE.html#defining_a_mixin&lt;/a&gt;. In this example, I&amp;rsquo;m going to reference another mixin &amp;ndash; Compass&amp;rsquo;s text-shadow plugin &amp;ndash; after generating the string of shadows I want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bc..  @mixin text-3d($size: 5, $directionX: 1, $directionY: 1, $blur: 1px, $color: black ) {
    @if unitless($blur) {
        @warn &amp;quot;Assuming #{$blur} to be in pixels&amp;quot;;
        $blur: 1px &lt;em&gt; $blur;
    }
    $string: &amp;#39;&amp;#39;;
    @for $i from 1 through $size {
        $string: $string + ( #{$i &lt;/em&gt; $directionX}px #{$i * $directionY}px $blur $color );
        @if $i &amp;lt; $size {
            $string: $string + &amp;#39;, &amp;#39;;
        }
    }
    @include text-shadow(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;hljs undefined&quot;&gt;    #{$string}
)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p. Pretty simple: this looks and works a lot like a function in JS/PHP. I accept a size parameter, which determines how many shadows to create (my examples above have five), then two direction parameters. This lets you send your 3d text down and to the right (1, 1), up and to the right (1, -1), up and to the left (-1, -1) or down and to the left (-1, 1). You can even use values like (-1, -0.5) to have the text go at 22.5&amp;deg; rather than 45&amp;deg;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the mixin is as simple as this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bc..  @include text-3d( 3, -1, -1, 0, $someColor );&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/color-ripples-canvas-toy</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/color-ripples-canvas-toy"/><title>Color Ripples: a Canvas Toy</title><updated>Sun Sep 11 2011 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a little bit of colorful distraction for a rainy afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 500px&quot; src=&quot;http://jsfiddle.net/nate/dyVPR/embedded/result,js,html&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Playing with @canvas@ is fun. However, you may notice, if you glance through the code, that there are really only five lines of code that are canvas-specific. (A few more if you count the setup.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{% highlight js %}
var $canvas = $( &amp;#39;canvas&amp;#39; ),
    canvas = $canvas[0],
    ctx = canvas.getContext( &amp;#39;2d&amp;#39; ),&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;hljs undefined&quot;&gt;drawPoint = function( x, y, radius, color ) {
    ctx.fillStyle = color;
    ctx.beginPath();
    ctx.arc( x, y, radius, 0, Math.PI * 2, false );
    ctx.closePath();
    ctx.fill();
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the code for, well, drawing a circle. &lt;em&gt;All&lt;/em&gt; of the rest of it is just various math and adjustments on where and how to draw those circles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent basically all of my highschool math courses messing around with &amp;quot;my graphing calculator&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://education.ti.com/educationportal/sites/US/productDetail/us_ti83p.html&quot;&gt;http://education.ti.com/educationportal/sites/US/productDetail/us_ti83p.html&lt;/a&gt; and &amp;quot;TI Basic&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TI-BASIC&quot;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TI-BASIC&lt;/a&gt;. I made a little magic eight ball program that gave different responses based on a random number; I made programs to take care of the quadratic equation for me. (Note: I spent more time fussing with the formatting and look of the UI for entering numbers than I did with the calculations - I was a front-end developer in the making!) I finally dropped out of AP Calculus when being clever about my calculator could no longer make up for the fact that I wasn&amp;#39;t learning a lick of math.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m grateful for what exposure I had to code - ultimately, even that time messing with TI Basic helped me find my way to a great career. But I can&amp;#39;t help but wish that somebody - &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; adult in my life - had noticed that I spent all my time trying vainly to do stuff with computers and said, &amp;quot;You know, that might not be so wholly irrelevant to his future...&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I can tell, every developer I know fends off multiple unsolicited recruitment emails a month: America needs people to write code and it wants to pay them for it. My school acted like the most important thing about computers was making sure we didn&amp;#39;t check our email on the &lt;em&gt;for-research&lt;/em&gt; computers in the library. (I got Saturday school for this once.) Couldn&amp;#39;t the public schools have noticed that education in computers &amp;amp; code might be a good investment back in the &amp;#39;90s?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Couldn&amp;#39;t there be a whole Math track for kids who&amp;#39;re interested in applying it to code? Can you imagine how much fun it would have been to immediately try out the formula for slope on a visual toy you wrote as homework?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For that matter: are public schools aware of this &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway: I actually had a great highschool Math teacher. Hell, I&amp;#39;d pay a lot of money at this point in my life to go back, sit in that musty portable classroom in Spanaway, Washington and have him teach me all about linear equations to help me draw pretty, moving pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/compass</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/compass"/><title>A Five-Minute Introduction to Compass</title><updated>Tue Sep 13 2011 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;section&gt;
h1. A Five-Minute Introduction to Compass

h3. by Nate Eagle
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
h2. We have a problem.

h3(step). CSS is complicated.
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Want to change one of the major colors your site uses?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&quot;step&quot;&gt;Want an element to be sized relative to another element?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&quot;step&quot;&gt;Want to serve a single stylesheet for performance reasons, but keep your styles organized in different files?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&quot;step&quot;&gt;Want to establish a consistent vertical rhythm?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
h2. It&amp;#39;s all possible.

h3(step). It&amp;#39;s just a &lt;em&gt;pain&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
h2.  We have a problem.

h3(step). CSS is getting &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; complicated.

&lt;div class=&quot;step&quot;&gt;
{% highlight css %}
body {
  background-image: url(/images/noise.png), -webkit-gradient(radial, circle farthest-corner, 0, circle farthest-corner, 100, color-stop(0%, rgba(36, 56, 66, 0.8)), color-stop(100%, rgba(18, 28, 33, 0.9)));
  background-image: url(/images/noise.png), -webkit-radial-gradient(circle farthest-corner, rgba(36, 56, 66, 0.8), rgba(18, 28, 33, 0.9));
  background-image: url(/images/noise.png), -moz-radial-gradient(circle farthest-corner, rgba(36, 56, 66, 0.8), rgba(18, 28, 33, 0.9));
  background-image: url(/images/noise.png), -o-radial-gradient(circle farthest-corner, rgba(36, 56, 66, 0.8), rgba(18, 28, 33, 0.9));
  background-image: url(/images/noise.png), -ms-radial-gradient(circle farthest-corner, rgba(36, 56, 66, 0.8), rgba(18, 28, 33, 0.9));
  background-image: url(/images/noise.png), radial-gradient(circle farthest-corner, rgba(36, 56, 66, 0.8), rgba(18, 28, 33, 0.9));
}
{% endhighlight %}
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;

h2. Compass, with SASS, is a framework for removing the &lt;em&gt;pain&lt;/em&gt; from CSS.

&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;

h2. &amp;quot;Want to change one of the major colors your site uses?&amp;quot;

h3(step). SASS gives us &lt;em&gt;variables&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
{% highlight sass %}
$backgroundColor: hsl( 200, 20%, 20% );
$color: hsl( 200, 90%, 50% );

body {
    background-color: $backgroundColor;
    color: $color;
}

h1 {
    color: complement( $color );
}

h2 {
    color: lighten( $color, 10% );
}

p {
    color: $color;
}

strong {
    color: adjust-hue( $color, 100deg );
}
{% endhighlight %}
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;

h2. &amp;quot;Want an element to be sized relative to another element?&amp;quot;

h3(step). SASS gives us &lt;em&gt;operations&lt;/em&gt;.

&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
{% highlight sass %}
$container: 600px;
$spacing: 20px;
$rightRail: ( $container / 3 ) - $spacing;
$river: ( 2 * ( $container / 3 ) ) - $spacing;

.container {
    width: $container;
}

.river,
.right-rail {
    margin: $spacing / 2;
}

.river {
    width: $river;
}

.right-rail {
    width: $rightRail;
}
{% endhighlight %}
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;

h2. &amp;quot;Want to serve a single stylesheet for performance reasons, but keep your styles organized in different files?&amp;quot;

h3(step). Compass gives us &lt;em&gt;imports&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
{% highlight sass %}
@import &amp;quot;compass/reset&amp;quot;;
@import &amp;quot;compass/css3&amp;quot;;
@import &amp;quot;syntax-friendly.scss&amp;quot;;
@import &amp;quot;fonts.scss&amp;quot;;
{% endhighlight %}
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
h2. &amp;quot;Want to establish a consistent vertical rhythm?&amp;quot;

h3(step). Compass gives us &lt;em&gt;mixins&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;section&gt;
{% highlight sass %}
@import &amp;quot;compass/typography/vertical_rhythm&amp;quot;;

$base-font-size: 16px;
$base-line-height: 24px;
$default-rhythm-border-style: solid;
$relative-font-sizing: false;

h1 {
    @include adjust-font-size-to( 72px );
    @include adjust-leading-to( 8 );
    @include margin-trailer( 1 );
}
{% endhighlight %}
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
h2. CSS is getting more complicated.

h3(step). Compass&amp;#39;s mixins make complex,&lt;br&gt; multi-vendor output&amp;nbsp;simple.
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
h2. Remember this?

{% highlight sass %}
body {
  background-image: url(/images/noise.png), -webkit-gradient(radial, circle farthest-corner, 0, circle farthest-corner, 100, color-stop(0%, rgba(36, 56, 66, 0.8)), color-stop(100%, rgba(18, 28, 33, 0.9)));
  background-image: url(/images/noise.png), -webkit-radial-gradient(circle farthest-corner, rgba(36, 56, 66, 0.8), rgba(18, 28, 33, 0.9));
  background-image: url(/images/noise.png), -moz-radial-gradient(circle farthest-corner, rgba(36, 56, 66, 0.8), rgba(18, 28, 33, 0.9));
  background-image: url(/images/noise.png), -o-radial-gradient(circle farthest-corner, rgba(36, 56, 66, 0.8), rgba(18, 28, 33, 0.9));
  background-image: url(/images/noise.png), -ms-radial-gradient(circle farthest-corner, rgba(36, 56, 66, 0.8), rgba(18, 28, 33, 0.9));
  background-image: url(/images/noise.png), radial-gradient(circle farthest-corner, rgba(36, 56, 66, 0.8), rgba(18, 28, 33, 0.9));
}
{% endhighlight %}
&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;section&gt;
h2. With Compass: 

{% highlight sass %}
body {
    @include background-image(
        url( /images/noise.png ),
        radial-gradient(
            circle farthest-corner,
            transparentize( lighten( $backgroundColor, 10% ), 0.2 ),
            transparentize( $backgroundColor, 0.1 )
        )&lt;br&gt;    );
}
{% endhighlight %}
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
h2. Is Compass worth it for you? 
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
h2. Do you...

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class=&quot;step&quot;&gt;Work on large sites with big stylesheets?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&quot;step&quot;&gt;Use CSS3?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&quot;step&quot;&gt;Maintain sites after they&amp;#39;re launched?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&quot;step&quot;&gt;Have compassion for others who do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

h3(step). THEN YES.
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
h2. Compass is the future of CSS.

h3(step). Try it today, or play catch-up tomorrow.
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
h2. Want to get started?

h3(step). Talk to me!
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
h2. Thank you!

h3. Fin
&lt;/section&gt;

</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/easier-post-creation-for-jekyll-with-bash</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/easier-post-creation-for-jekyll-with-bash"/><title>Easier Post Creation for Jekyll with Bash</title><updated>Wed Sep 21 2011 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The biggest reason to use &amp;quot;Jekyll&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is, in my opinion, its simplicity and convenience for people who work with files for a living. If changing directories and making files is what you do all day, then writing posts by creating files will just feel like The Way It Should Be. You&amp;#39;ll love that you don&amp;#39;t have to log into a web interface to add posts. If you&amp;#39;d &lt;em&gt;rather&lt;/em&gt; log into a web app, I&amp;#39;m not sure why on earth you&amp;#39;d use Jekyll: it&amp;#39;s too minimalistic to offer any huge advantages over the many great CMSs out there today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few weeks of using Jekyll, I found that it was a bit of a chore to think of today&amp;#39;s date and type it out whenever I wanted to create a post. Since I was adding a second post type called bits to my blog for frequent, short posts it became even more of an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I created a bash script to make this easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve written about three or four bash scripts in my entire life, so it takes me a bit of time and work to look everything up. In case you&amp;#39;re in the same boat, I&amp;#39;m including the script below along with URLs for the references I used along with a few notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s the complete script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{% highlight bash %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;create-a-new-post-with-today-s-date-and-prompt-for-the-title-&quot;&gt;Create a new post with today&amp;#39;s date and prompt for the title.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;config&quot;&gt;Config&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;editor=&amp;quot;vim&amp;quot;
format=&amp;quot;textile&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;get-layout-via-getopts-l-&quot;&gt;Get layout via getopts (-l)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;-&quot;&gt;--&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;http-wiki-bash-hackers-org-howto-getopts_tutorial&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.bash-hackers.org/howto/getopts_tutorial&quot;&gt;http://wiki.bash-hackers.org/howto/getopts_tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;while getopts &amp;quot;:l:&amp;quot; opt; do
    case $opt in
        l)
            layout=$OPTARG
            ;;
        :) echo &amp;quot;$opt requires an argument&amp;quot; &amp;gt;&amp;amp;2
            exit 1
            ;;
    esac
done&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;set-default-config-values&quot;&gt;Set default config values&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;-&quot;&gt;--&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;http-www-cyberciti-biz-tips-howto-setting-default-values-for-shell-variables-html&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyberciti.biz/tips/howto-setting-default-values-for-shell-variables.html&quot;&gt;http://www.cyberciti.biz/tips/howto-setting-default-values-for-shell-variables.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;: ${layout:=&amp;quot;post&amp;quot;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;i-like-giving-myself-a-polite-greeting-&quot;&gt;I like giving myself a polite greeting.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;-&quot;&gt;--&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;date-codes-http-linux-about-com-od-commands-l-blcmdl1_date-htm&quot;&gt;Date codes: &lt;a href=&quot;http://linux.about.com/od/commands/l/blcmdl1_date.htm&quot;&gt;http://linux.about.com/od/commands/l/blcmdl1_date.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;echo &amp;quot;---&amp;quot;
echo &amp;quot;Creating a new ${layout} for&amp;quot; &lt;code&gt;date +%A&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;%B&amp;quot; &amp;quot;%e&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;%Y&lt;/code&gt;&amp;quot;.&amp;quot;
echo &amp;quot;&amp;quot;
read -p &amp;quot;Enter the title: &amp;quot; title &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;turn-spaces-into-dashes&quot;&gt;Turn spaces into dashes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;-&quot;&gt;--&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;http-stackoverflow-com-questions-1469849-how-to-split-one-string-into-multiple-strings-in-bash-shell&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1469849/how-to-split-one-string-into-multiple-strings-in-bash-shell&quot;&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1469849/how-to-split-one-string-into-multiple-strings-in-bash-shell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for word in $title
do
    dashedTitle=${dashedTitle}-${word}
done&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;convert-title-to-lowercase&quot;&gt;Convert title to lowercase&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;-&quot;&gt;--&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;http-stackoverflow-com-questions-2264428-converting-string-to-lower-case-in-bash-shell-scripting&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/2264428/converting-string-to-lower-case-in-bash-shell-scripting&quot;&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/2264428/converting-string-to-lower-case-in-bash-shell-scripting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;http-www-kclug-org-pipermail-kclug-2003-april-015084-html&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kclug.org/pipermail/kclug/2003-April/015084.html&quot;&gt;http://www.kclug.org/pipermail/kclug/2003-April/015084.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;dashedTitle=&amp;quot;&lt;code&gt;echo ${dashedTitle} | tr &amp;#39;[A-Z]&amp;#39; &amp;#39;[a-z]&amp;#39;&lt;/code&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;create-a-filename-with-the-date-dashed-title-and-format&quot;&gt;Create a filename with the date, dashed title, and format&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;filename=&amp;quot;&lt;code&gt;date +%Y-%m-%d&lt;/code&gt;${dashedTitle}.${format}&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;echo $filename&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;touch $filename&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;add-initial-yaml-to-the-top-of-the-new-bit&quot;&gt;Add initial YAML to the top of the new bit&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;echo &amp;quot;---&amp;quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; $filename
echo &amp;quot;layout: ${layout}&amp;quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; $filename
echo &amp;quot;title: \&amp;quot;${title}\&amp;quot;&amp;quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; $filename
echo &amp;quot;summary:&amp;quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; $filename
echo &amp;quot;---&amp;quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; $filename
echo &amp;quot;&amp;quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; $filename&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;open-in-vim-and-go-to-the-end-of-the-file-&quot;&gt;Open in vim and go to the end of the file ( + )&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;-&quot;&gt;--&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;http-stackoverflow-com-questions-268123-vim-how-to-start-inserting-at-the-end-of-the-file-in-one-step&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/268123/vim-how-to-start-inserting-at-the-end-of-the-file-in-one-step&quot;&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/268123/vim-how-to-start-inserting-at-the-end-of-the-file-in-one-step&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;${editor} + $filename
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#39;ll notice I created a layout option that can be passed in using @-l@. I use multiple post layouts on the blog, the most important of which are &lt;em&gt;post&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;bit&lt;/em&gt;. Bits are very small posts that aren&amp;#39;t included in the main list on the homepage or in my Atom feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created two aliases (these should go in your @.bashrc@ file) to simplify creation of posts and bits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{% highlight bash %}
alias post=&amp;quot;./post.sh&amp;quot;
alias bit=&amp;quot;./post.sh -l bit&amp;quot;
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The script uses post as the default type. On running, the script&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prompts me for a title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;uses today&amp;#39;s date plus a lowercase and dash-separated version of the title for the new post&amp;#39;s filename&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prepopulates the post with the YAML I use for posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;opens the new post in vim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to create this post, I typed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{% highlight bash %}
$ post
$ ---
$ Creating a new post for Wednesday, September 21, 2011.
$ 
$ Enter the title: Easier Post Creation for Jekyll with Bash
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This created @2011-09-21-easier-post-creation-for-jekyll-with-bash.textile@, added my YAML, and popped it up in vim. Nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;h3. One last item on my wish list &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;d really like to find a solution for tab completion when I have a directory full of similarly prefixed files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{% highlight bash %}
2011-08-30-upholstery-a-css3-pattern.textile                 2011-09-09-my-first-compass-mixin-text-3d.textile            2011-09-21-easier-post-creation-for-jekyll-with-bash.textile
2011-08-31-how-to-output-curly-brackets-in-jekyll.textile    2011-09-11-color-ripples-canvas-toy.textile                  2011-09-21-open-a-directory-in-finder-from-terminal.textile
2011-08-31-jekyll-not-parsing-includes.textile               2011-09-13-compass.textile 
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I have a directory like the one above, I&amp;#39;d love to be able to type @col&lt;TAB&gt;@ and have it expand to @2011-09-11-color-ripples-canvas-toy.textile@. In other words, the completion regex would match for a date string and disregard that prefix when matching filenames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may well be possible - even trivial - for someone smarter than I. I did find a great example of &amp;quot;something similar&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/3238983/writing-a-custom-bash-completion-rule&quot;&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/3238983/writing-a-custom-bash-completion-rule&lt;/a&gt; for vim that&amp;#39;ll let you add a @.completion@ file to any directory with a static prefix that will allow you to type, say, @vim &lt;TAB&gt;@ and have it expand to @vim _myprefix@.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you have any suggestions for my bash script - as I said, I&amp;#39;m a bash n00b, and feedback is welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/open-a-directory-in-finder-from-terminal</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/open-a-directory-in-finder-from-terminal"/><title>Open a Directory in Finder from Terminal</title><updated>Wed Sep 21 2011 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finder may not be the worst part of OS X, but it&amp;#39;s a contender. Regardless: you may sometimes wish to open your working directory in the command line in Finder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{% highlight bash %}
open .
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/animate-anything-with-jquerys-animate</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/animate-anything-with-jquerys-animate"/><title>Animate Anything With jQuery's .animate()</title><updated>Sun Oct 02 2011 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;jQuery&amp;#39;s .animate() function is lovely: it&amp;#39;s got great queueing built in and makes animating in JS totally painless. But it&amp;#39;s limited to CSS properties. You can animate opacity, position, and more, but if you want to animate something in a very customized way, it&amp;#39;s not as obvious how .animate() can help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;d been meaning to try working around this a while ago, but I never got around to it. This weekend at the jQuery conference in Boston, I saw &amp;quot;Corey Frang&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://gnarf.net/&quot;&gt;http://gnarf.net/&lt;/a&gt; give a nice talk about how animation works in jQuery. He pointed out that it&amp;#39;d be awfully nice to be able to be able to use .animate() without needing a CSS property and that he&amp;#39;s hoping it can get worked into the 1.7 release for jQuery. He pointed out that it&amp;#39;s possible to work around the requirement right now, though, by using a fake CSS property, and he showed an example by &amp;quot;Cowboy&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://benalman.com/&quot;&gt;http://benalman.com/&lt;/a&gt; (Ben Alman) that animated a string of text in a really cool way: it began with all of the text hidden, then it progressively revealed the text as it if it were unrolling, or being typed in. It even used a bounce effect (via easing). This was a perfect example of a great effect that makes sense to use .animate() for, but sure as hell isn&amp;#39;t a CSS property.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I decided to try to recreate Cowboy&amp;#39;s example on my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe
    style=&quot;width: 600px; height: 600px&quot;
    src=&quot;http://jsfiddle.net/nate/Grt5e/embedded/result,js,html,css&quot;
    allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The animation itself is surprisingly smooth. I have it output the latter segment of the text string so that the element containing the text doesn&amp;#39;t change shape and size as it appears. It also prevents having the first few letters of words at the ends of lines appear before dropping the word to the line below as it gets long enough to wrap. Sometimes this might be a desireable effect: if you want it to look like the words are being typed live, for instance. In that case, just omit the span and the second substring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway: I guess it&amp;#39;s time to hunt down Cowboy&amp;#39;s example and see how I could have made mine better. I&amp;#39;m also eager to try other inventive ways to animate page elements - now it&amp;#39;s just a matter of getting the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/invert-the-screen-colors-on-your-mac</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/invert-the-screen-colors-on-your-mac"/><title>Invert the Screen Colors on Your Mac</title><updated>Sun Oct 02 2011 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend at the jQuery conference in Boston, an attendee informed Adam Sontag during his presentation with Rick Waldron that he could invert the screen colors on his mac to make the text more visible by pressing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bc. Control + Option + Command + 8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p. A handy thing to know for making photographs look hilarious.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/sharpening-the-vim</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/sharpening-the-vim"/><title>Sharpening the Vim</title><updated>Mon Nov 07 2011 00:00:00 GMT-0500 (EST)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m somewhat ambivalent about Franklin Covey in general, but I must acknowledge that using the metaphor &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.franklincovey.com/blog/tag/habit-7-sharpen-the-saw&quot;&gt;sharpening the saw&lt;/a&gt; to describe the vital habit of self-improvement is pretty awesome, largely because it implies that the most important thing in life is going around with a sharp-ass saw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been a happy Vim user since &lt;a href=&quot;http://concisionandconcinnity.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Ian McCracken&lt;/a&gt; introduced me to it a couple years ago. I&amp;#39;m not really sure it makes me a better programmer or person, especially since I&amp;#39;m not really sure that editor speed is the limiting factor in my work productivity. (I can type much, much faster than I can usefully think. As &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crockford.com/&quot;&gt;Douglas Crockford&lt;/a&gt; said at the recent Capitol JS Conference (paraphrased), &amp;quot;Most of the time you spend programming isn&amp;#39;t spent coding: it&amp;#39;s spent staring into the abyss saying, &amp;#39;My God, what have I done?&amp;#39;&amp;quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, Vim makes entering and editing text feel effortless and elegant rather than frustrating. And, really, if you enter/edit text for a living, priority number one is making it an enjoyable or at least endurable task. For me, the big thing is that I don&amp;#39;t have to switch back and forth between a mouse and the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best intro to Vim is probably just to pull up your terminal and type &lt;code&gt;vimtutor&lt;/code&gt;, an interactive tutorial that takes maybe twenty to thirty minutes. It&amp;#39;ll teach you everything you need to know to get started. But as &lt;a href=&quot;http://yannesposito.com/&quot;&gt;Yann Esposito&lt;/a&gt; says in his excellent &lt;a href=&quot;http://yannesposito.com/Scratch/en/blog/Learn-Vim-Progressively/&quot;&gt;Learn Vim Progressively&lt;/a&gt; entry: &amp;quot;Learning vim will be painful at first. It will take time. It will be a lot like playing a music instrument.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve used Vim for, I dunno, two years now, and it&amp;#39;s easy to settle into ruts. I&amp;#39;ve got ways of accomplishing everything I need, but they&amp;#39;re not all elegant. Last week, &lt;a href=&quot;http://artzstudio.com&quot;&gt;Dave Artz&lt;/a&gt;, the AOLer who hired me (high five, Dave!) started trying out Vim. The last few days, he&amp;#39;s IMed me repeatedly asking about different ways to do things, plenty of which I had to look up. It was a good reminder that there&amp;#39;s lots I have yet to effectively learn or internalize, and that my ability to play this particular instrument still has plenty of room to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is awesome. So: that lengthy introduction aside, these are a few of the things I&amp;#39;ve had to look up that I want to write down so that I can remember them for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;vim-pbcopy-on-os-x&quot;&gt;Vim &amp;amp; pbcopy on OS X&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;pbcopy&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;pbpaste&lt;/code&gt; are the bees&amp;#39; knees: they&amp;#39;re commands that use OS X&amp;#39;s system clipboard (&amp;quot;paste board&amp;quot; is the OS X name, I guess) via terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding this mapping to your &lt;code&gt;.vimrc&lt;/code&gt; will let you use &lt;code&gt;ctrl-x&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;ctrl-c&lt;/code&gt; to cut/copy the current visual selection to OS X&amp;#39;s pasteboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{% highlight vim %}
vmap &lt;C-x&gt; :!pbcopy&lt;CR&gt;
vmap &lt;C-c&gt; :w !pbcopy&lt;CR&gt;&lt;CR&gt;
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via &lt;a href=&quot;http://drydevelopment.com/blog/vim-pbcopy-on-os-x.&quot;&gt;drydevelopment.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;change-the-colorscheme&quot;&gt;Change the Colorscheme&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one&amp;#39;s super dumb, but when I was trying to find a decent colorscheme for Vim (I&amp;#39;m using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vim.org/scripts/script.php?script_id=105&quot;&gt;desert&lt;/a&gt;,) I kept closing Vim, editing my .vimrc, and reopening Vim. LIKE A CHUMP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;:colorscheme desert&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-the-leader&quot;&gt;Using the Leader&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been pretty resistant to customizing Vim. I don&amp;#39;t like reassigning default functionality till I&amp;#39;m really sure I understand it. What if I break a feature I haven&amp;#39;t discovered yet because of today&amp;#39;s shortsightedness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Vim has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://stevelosh.com/blog/2010/09/coming-home-to-vim/#using-the-leader&quot;&gt;leader key&lt;/a&gt;. the entire role of which is to give you a whole bunch of blank namespace to create custom commands. The default is &lt;code&gt;\&lt;/code&gt;, but Steve Losh (the dude who wrote the article I just linked to) argues (to me persuasively) that &lt;code&gt;,&lt;/code&gt; (the comma) is easier to reach and not used for anything else. Nice: the freedom to make useful custom stuff without worrying about messing things up for myself later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, actually, &lt;a href=&quot;http://stevelosh.com/blog/2010/09/coming-home-to-vim/&quot;&gt;that whole article&lt;/a&gt; is worth reading. He explains his whole &lt;code&gt;.vimrc&lt;/code&gt; file in the most detail I&amp;#39;ve encountered. Well, maybe I should say that he explains it with the fewest assumptions about existing knowledge on the part of his reader. Which I appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;jsbeautify&quot;&gt;jsBeautify&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vim.org/scripts/script.php?script_id=2727&quot;&gt;jsBeautify&lt;/a&gt; will clean up messy, inconsistently formatted JavaScript file with a single command. Awesome, but I need to figure out how much work would be involved in modifying it to follow &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.jquery.com/JQuery_Core_Style_Guidelines.&quot;&gt;the jQuery style guidelines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;remove-unwanted-whitespace&quot;&gt;Remove Unwanted Whitespace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s simple to &lt;a href=&quot;http://vim.wikia.com/wiki/Remove_unwanted_spaces&quot;&gt;remove unwanted whitespace&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bq.. Delete all trailing whitespace (at the end of each line) with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;:%s/\s\+$//&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More rarely, a user might want to delete whitespace at the beginning of each line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;:%s/^\s\+&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;comment-out-a-range-of-lines&quot;&gt;Comment Out a Range of Lines&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too lengthy to quote, here&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://vim.wikia.com/wiki/Commenting_out_a_range_of_lines.&quot;&gt;the page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;wrap-visual-selection-in-an-html-tag-&quot;&gt;Wrap visual selection in an HTML tag.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{% highlight vim %}
vmap &lt;Leader&gt;w &lt;Esc&gt;:call VisualHTMLTagWrap()&lt;CR&gt;
function! VisualHTMLTagWrap()
let tag = input(&amp;quot;Tag to wrap block: &amp;quot;)
if len(tag) &amp;gt; 0
normal &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; if &amp;amp;selection == &amp;#39;exclusive&amp;#39; exe &amp;quot;normal i&amp;lt;/&amp;quot;.tag.&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;quot; else exe &amp;quot;normal a&amp;lt;/&amp;quot;.tag.&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;quot; endif normal&lt;/code&gt;&amp;lt;
exe &amp;quot;normal i&amp;lt;&amp;quot;.tag.&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;quot;
normal `&amp;lt;
endif
endfunction
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p. Put it in &lt;code&gt;~/.vim/scripts/wrapwithtag.vim&lt;/code&gt; and enable in &lt;code&gt;~/.vimrc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bc. :au Filetype html,xml source ~/.vim/scripts/wrapwithtag.vim&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p. When editing HTML file, visually highlight text and press {Leader} w, enter tag name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;scrolling-quickly&quot;&gt;Scrolling Quickly&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p. I tend to move quickly around a file either by typing a linenumber + G (which is awesome but too precise to be useful, many times) or holding down &lt;code&gt;j&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;k&lt;/code&gt;. (LIKE A CHUMP.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scrolling is easy. The most useful, IMHO, is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bc. ^D ^U scroll half a page up, down&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there are &lt;a href=&quot;http://tnerual.eriogerg.free.fr/vimqrc.html.&quot;&gt;others&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;adjust-window-size&quot;&gt;Adjust Window Size&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;vsplit&lt;/code&gt; is basically the killer feature of Vim. When I showed &lt;a href=&quot;http://artzstudio.com&quot;&gt;Dave&lt;/a&gt; that he could &lt;code&gt;split&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;vsplit&lt;/code&gt;, and re&lt;code&gt;split&lt;/code&gt; any number of windows he chose on to infinity he basically flipped. I always keep my windows equally sized with &lt;code&gt;C-W + =&lt;/code&gt;, but he wanted to adjust the sizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For vertically split windows, use &lt;code&gt;C-W + &amp;lt;&lt;/code&gt; to decrease the current window&amp;#39;s size and &lt;code&gt;C-W + &amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; to increase it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For horizintally split windows, use &lt;code&gt;C-W + plus&lt;/code&gt; to make the window taller. (That just broke my typographic convention. It&amp;#39;s control-w plus the, uh, plus key.) Use &lt;code&gt;C-W + -&lt;/code&gt; to make the window shorter. (That wasn&amp;#39;t much better, was it?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;clear-search-results-with-leader-space&quot;&gt;Clear Search Results with Leader + Space&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually clear search results by typing &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; plus a furious smattering of random letters. Crudely effective. But with the new leader key, I was willing to bind &lt;code&gt;leader + space&lt;/code&gt; to accomplish this more elegantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bc. nnoremap &lt;leader&gt;&lt;space&gt; :noh&lt;cr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;add-a-line-of-equal-signs-for-documentation&quot;&gt;Add a line of equal signs for documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lines of equal signs look awesome. Proof:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;bc-lines-of-equal-signs-look-awesome&quot;&gt;bc. Lines of Equal Signs Look Awesome&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bind &lt;code&gt;leader + 1&lt;/code&gt; (or, you know, &lt;code&gt;leader&lt;/code&gt; + ANYTHING) to create a new line below your current line of the same length of equal signs. Nice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bc. nnoremap &lt;leader&gt;1 yypVr=&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-later&quot;&gt;More Later&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll add more to another entry whenever I&amp;#39;ve got too many Vim-related tabs open in Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/fix-indentation-in-vim-with-=</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/fix-indentation-in-vim-with-="/><title>Fix indentation in Vim with =</title><updated>Thu Nov 01 2012 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Want to correctly indent the line you&amp;#39;re on? @==@
Want to do the whole file? @gg=G@&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is particularly useful if you&amp;#39;ve recently been converted to two-space indentation for JavaScript files and all your files use four-space indentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;More info.&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://vim.wikia.com/wiki/Indenting_source_code&quot;&gt;http://vim.wikia.com/wiki/Indenting_source_code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/preview-textile-files-from-vim</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/preview-textile-files-from-vim"/><title>Preview Textile files from Vim</title><updated>Thu Nov 01 2012 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Editing that README.textile for your Github project? Working on a new post in Jekyll? &amp;quot;Textile for VIM&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vim.org/scripts/script.php?script_id=2305&quot;&gt;http://www.vim.org/scripts/script.php?script_id=2305&lt;/a&gt; lets those of us on OS X view a preview of the rendered file in a new browser tab with @&lt;leader&gt;rp@.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/what-is-the-difference-between-font-typeface</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/what-is-the-difference-between-font-typeface"/><title>What is the difference between font &amp; typeface?</title><updated>Thu Nov 01 2012 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every so often I&amp;#39;ll be out taking a walk and it occurs to me that I still haven&amp;#39;t figured out exactly what the difference is between the term &lt;em&gt;font&lt;/em&gt; and the term &lt;em&gt;typeface&lt;/em&gt;. I know they&amp;#39;re not the same. I know designers&amp;#39; eyes roll back into their heads when the terms are used interchangeably. Inevitably, I forget about the question in a minute or two and never resolve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;WONDER NO MORE, Nate&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Typeface#Terminology&quot;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Typeface#Terminology&lt;/a&gt;. A font is the &amp;quot;specific member of a type family such as roman, boldface, or italic type&amp;quot;. Typeface, on the other hand, is what we usually talk about: a family of related fonts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Yo, dude, what font is that?&amp;quot;
&amp;quot;I believe that&amp;#39;s roman, actually.&amp;quot;
&amp;quot;Roman, huh? Looked kinda like Futura or something to me.&amp;quot;
&amp;quot;Ah, you meant to inquire about the typeface.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to winning friends and influencing people in this manner for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/prevent-orphans-in-text-with-jekyll-(liquid)</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/prevent-orphans-in-text-with-jekyll-(liquid)"/><title>Prevent Orphans in Text with Jekyll (Liquid)</title><updated>Thu Nov 15 2012 00:00:00 GMT-0500 (EST)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having orphaned words in titles is irritating and lame. I was pleased to find that it was relatively easy to insert an &amp;amp;nbsp; entity in front of the final word in a string in Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/4081163.js?file=prevent-orphans&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/blog-redesign</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/blog-redesign"/><title>Blog Redesign</title><updated>Fri Mar 08 2013 00:00:00 GMT-0500 (EST)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been working on this off and on, and I finally decided just to launch it since a) it will never be perfect, and b) I will not be getting significantly more free time any time in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;h2. We&amp;#39;re responsive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;d like to note that back in 2006, I read a post by some guy about some JavaScript he wrote that would change the body class based on the width of the browser window. He had a demo that showed a web page adjusting the number of columns in its layout based on the window size. I bookmarked it and briefly tried to create a design for my blog based around that idea, but then I probably got bored and watched some Simpsons episodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seven years later, responsive design has taken over the internet. To be fair, it matters a lot more now that we&amp;#39;re using tons of mobile devices. But it&amp;#39;s interesting to remember that lots of things don&amp;#39;t take off when they become possible, they take off when they matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;h2. @font-face&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re rocking custom fonts, just like the rest of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;h2. Grunt JS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m using Grunt to automate everything I can. It compiles my scss, minifies my js, runs jekyll, and irons my laundry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;h2. No longer served by Github Pages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought it was fun to use Github&amp;#39;s pages to host my site last time. Then I realized that it didn&amp;#39;t really matter because I&amp;#39;m paying for a VPS anyway. Also I&amp;#39;m doing all my compilation on my own with Grunt, so the fact that Github will run a Jekyll process on its side wasn&amp;#39;t really a perk anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is, of course, still _on_ Github. You can check out &amp;quot;the repo&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/neagle/nateeagle.com&quot;&gt;https://github.com/neagle/nateeagle.com&lt;/a&gt; if you feel like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;h2. And actual posts, maybe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But no promises.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/open-new-tabs-in-iterm-in-the-current-directory</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/open-new-tabs-in-iterm-in-the-current-directory"/><title>Open new tabs in iTerm in the current directory</title><updated>Fri Mar 08 2013 00:00:00 GMT-0500 (EST)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;!(l-full){max-width:924px}/images/posts/iterm-preferences.png!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s easy to tell iTerm to use the current directory (@pwd@) for any new tabs, which is what I want to happen 90% of the time I open a new tab. I can&amp;#39;t believe I waited this long to figure out how to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change &lt;strong&gt;Preferences &amp;raquo; Profiles &amp;raquo; General &amp;raquo; Working Directory&lt;/strong&gt; to &amp;quot;Reuse previous session&amp;#39;s directory&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/game-review-from-yuan-zhou</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/game-review-from-yuan-zhou"/><title>Go Game Review from Yuan Zhou</title><updated>Tue Mar 12 2013 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I take go lessons from &amp;quot;Yuan Zhou&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://zhouyuan.com&quot;&gt;http://zhouyuan.com&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#39;ve played go for just over three years and despite my many character flaws have managed to make some progress. Last week, I decided to take more detailed notes than normal in an attempt to help the instruction sink in more deeply. It was also a chance to try to preserve some of the sayings and general advice that comes up in lessons - it&amp;#39;s one of my favorite things about Shifu&amp;#39;s style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eidogo-player-auto&quot; sgf=&quot;/sgf/cloudbrows_vs_bluegrass.sgf&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/automatic-project-based-gnu-screen-setup</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/automatic-project-based-gnu-screen-setup"/><title>Automatic, Grunt-Project-Based GNU Screen Setup</title><updated>Tue Mar 26 2013 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a wish list item: I&amp;#39;m writing about it now so that I remember what I wanted. Hopefully, I&amp;#39;ll find a chance to come back to this and actually build what I want. If I do, I&amp;#39;ll update the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love using GNU Screen to manage my workflow on projects. If you work entirely in the terminal, it&amp;#39;s great to have screens open with the different processes and files you need to juggle while working on something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, I might have these screens going simultaneously:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A grunt watch process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gruntfile.js&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My main plugin JS file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My main plugin SCSS file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A command line for compiling Grunt, maneuvering files around, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside screen, the shortcut @Ctrl+A, &amp;quot;@ brings up a list of open screens. Inside any individual screen, you can change the name with @Ctrl+A, A@. This is a great window-management feature that doesn&amp;#39;t rely on any OS Chrome, but it has a further advantage when you&amp;#39;re working remotely. Any time you get disconnected because you got up for lunch or, I don&amp;#39;t know, you stopped working for a while out of the desire to sleep during the dark period of the earth&amp;#39;s rotation, you can log back in and just @screen -r@ to hop back in exactly where you left off, all of your screens and processes just as you left them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also name your screen sessions with @screen -S name@, then disconnect and reconnect to them according to what you&amp;#39;re working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of setting up your project initially is still a bit of a pain, and it&amp;#39;s especially a pain on your Mac, where you lose any active screen sessions whenever the Mac gets restarted. Since my whole life as a developer is structured around Grunt projects, I&amp;#39;d love to have an automatic startup for screen that takes advantage of this predictable structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my wishlist item:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;i-go-to-the-root-directory-of-a-grunt-project-&quot;&gt;I go to the root directory of a Grunt project.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;i-type-grunt-screen-or-screen-or-whatever-&quot;&gt;I type &amp;quot;grunt screen&amp;quot; (or @screen@, or whatever).&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;grunt-or-my-startup-script-or-whatever-checks-to-see-if-i-m-in-a-screen-session-already-if-i-am-it-aborts-with-a-nice-message-&quot;&gt;Grunt, or my startup script, or whatever checks to see if I&amp;#39;m in a screen session already. If I am, it aborts with a nice message.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;then-it-checks-to-see-if-there-s-an-active-screen-session-for-this-project-&quot;&gt;Then it checks to see if there&amp;#39;s an active screen session for this project.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;if-there-is-it-resumes-it-&quot;&gt;If there is, it resumes it.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;if-not-it-starts-a-new-one-&quot;&gt;If not, it starts a new one.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;it-also-spins-up-some-default-screens-one-for-a-grunt-watch-process-and-a-few-others-based-on-my-gruntfile-js-there-could-be-logic-to-figure-out-what-some-key-files-are-or-there-could-just-be-a-section-of-the-config-where-important-files-are-listed-explicitly-&quot;&gt;It also spins up some default screens - one for a grunt watch process, and a few others based on my Gruntfile.js. There could be logic to figure out what some key files are, or there could just be a section of the config where important files are listed explicitly.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;if-i-m-not-inside-a-grunt-project-screen-starts-as-normal-&quot;&gt;If I&amp;#39;m not inside a Grunt project, screen starts as normal.&lt;/h1&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/ssh-bookmarks</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/ssh-bookmarks"/><title>SSH Bookmarks</title><updated>Tue Mar 26 2013 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve always wanted some command-line ssh bookmarks for servers I have to access frequently. I know, I could just set up a bunch of aliases, but then I have to remember arbitrary names for every server I want to access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that you can &amp;quot;use @~/.ssh/config@&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://kb.mediatemple.net/questions/1625/Using+an+SSH+Config+File&quot;&gt;http://kb.mediatemple.net/questions/1625/Using+an+SSH+Config+File&lt;/a&gt; to set up shortcuts for frequently accessed servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Host nateeagle
    HostName        nateeagle.com
    User            neagle
    IdentityFile    ~/.ssh/id_rsa.pub&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I just type @ssh nateeagle@ to access my VPS, for example. I still would love to be able to type @ssh ls@ or something like that to get a friendly, alphabetized list of all the sites I have shortcuts set up for. It&amp;#39;s relatively easy to pull open the config file in vim, but I&amp;#39;m spoiled by things like @brew list@ and @bower list@.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/import-a-whole-directory-with-sass-using-grunt</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/import-a-whole-directory-with-sass-using-grunt"/><title>Import a Whole Directory with Sass (Using Grunt)</title><updated>Sat Mar 30 2013 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been using &amp;quot;Compass&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://compass-style.org/&quot;&gt;http://compass-style.org/&lt;/a&gt; for almost two years. One of the biggest advantages of using Compass is the ability to separate the many concerns of my CSS into different files. I &lt;code&gt;@import&lt;/code&gt; them into the main stylesheet, and they&amp;#39;re all bundled together in a single file when they&amp;#39;re compiled. It&amp;#39;s hard to believe that there was a time I wrote all my CSS in a single file for performance reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over that time, I&amp;#39;ve gradually refined how I organize my files, especially after reading &amp;quot;Jonathan Snook&amp;#39;s SMACSS&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://smacss.com/&quot;&gt;http://smacss.com/&lt;/a&gt;. One thing I&amp;#39;ve wished I could do, over and over, is have a single import that will pull in a directory full of module files. In other words, I&amp;#39;d like to be able to put &lt;code&gt;@import &amp;quot;modules&amp;quot;;&lt;/code&gt; and have it import all of the &lt;code&gt;_somemodule.scss&lt;/code&gt; files I have in the &lt;code&gt;modules&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this is not a feature Sass supports, and I imagine &amp;quot;this person is right about why&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4778627/is-it-possible-to-import-a-whole-directory-in-sass-using-import&quot;&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4778627/is-it-possible-to-import-a-whole-directory-in-sass-using-import&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4778627/is-it-possible-to-import-a-whole-directory-in-sass-using-import&quot;&gt;
This feature will never be part of Sass. One major reason is import order. In CSS, the files imported last can override the styles stated before. If you import a directory, how can you determine import order? There&amp;#39;s no way that doesn&amp;#39;t introduce some new level of complexity. By keeping a list of imports&amp;hellip; you&amp;#39;re being explicit with import order. This is essential if you want to be able to confidently override styles that are defined in another file or write mixins in one file and use them in another.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s fair enough, but I never want to try to override module styles from other modules. Any dependence on source order in my own CSS would be a flaw, from my perspective; I&amp;#39;d be quite satisfied with an arbitrarily-ordered import of a directory full of module styles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could fix this with a shell script, but these days I&amp;#39;m using &amp;quot;Grunt JS&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://gruntjs.com&quot;&gt;http://gruntjs.com&lt;/a&gt; as my compilation Swiss Army Knife. So I created a simple &amp;quot;custom task&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gruntjs/grunt/wiki/Creating-tasks&quot;&gt;https://github.com/gruntjs/grunt/wiki/Creating-tasks&lt;/a&gt; that will find any &lt;code&gt;_all.scss&lt;/code&gt; files and write &lt;code&gt;@import&lt;/code&gt; statements to them to import every other unerscore-prefixed file in the same directory. Then I can just add a &lt;code&gt;@import &amp;quot;modules/all&amp;quot;;&lt;/code&gt; to my &lt;code&gt;main.scss&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; When you prefix files with an underscore, Sass views them as &amp;quot;partials&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/docs/yardoc/file.SASS_REFERENCE.html#partials&quot;&gt;http://sass-lang.com/docs/yardoc/file.SASS_REFERENCE.html#partials&lt;/a&gt;, which don&amp;#39;t get compiled to their own @css@ files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s the custom task, which I saved in a @tasks@ directory off root. (You could also just include the @grunt.registerMultiTask@ without the @module.exports@ in your @Gruntfile.js@, but why create a mess? Grunt has good organization conventions.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{% highlight js %}
&amp;#39;use strict&amp;#39;;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;module.exports = function (grunt) {&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;hljs undefined&quot;&gt;grunt.registerMultiTask(
    'sass-directory-imports',
    'Write SASS @import statements to a single file to include a directory\'s entire contents dynamically.',
    function () {
        var files = this.filesSrc;
        var quiet = this.options().quiet;
        files.forEach(function (filepath) {
            // Create an array that we'll ultimately use to populate our includes file
            var newFileContents = [
                // Header
                '// This file imports all other underscore-prefixed .scss files in this directory.',
                '// It is automatically generated by the grunt compass-directory-includes task.',
                '// Do not directly modify this file.',
                ''
            ];
            var directory = filepath.substring(0, filepath.lastIndexOf('/'));

            // Search for underscore prefixed scss files
            // Then remove the file we're writing the imports to from that set
            var filesToInclude = grunt.file.expand([directory + '/_*.scss', '!' + filepath]);

            if (!quiet) {
                grunt.log.writeln('\n' + filepath.yellow + ':');
            }

            if (!quiet &amp;&amp; !filesToInclude.length) {
                grunt.log.writeln('No files found in ' + directory.cyan + ' to import.');
            }

            filesToInclude.forEach(function (includeFilepath) {

                // The include file is the filepath minus the directory slash and the
                // initial underscore
                var includeFile = includeFilepath.substring(includeFilepath.lastIndexOf('/') + 2);

                // Remove .scss extension
                includeFile = includeFile.replace('.scss', '');

                if (!quiet) {
                    grunt.log.writeln('Importing ' + includeFile.cyan);
                }

                newFileContents.push('@import &quot;' + includeFile + '&quot;;');
            });

            newFileContents = newFileContents.join('\n');
            grunt.file.write(filepath, newFileContents);
        });
    }
);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;};
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then in my @Gruntfile.js@ I include a block to configure the @sass-directory-imports@ task. I make sure there&amp;#39;s a line loading my project tasks, then I add the @sass-directory-imports@ task to my default. It should be before the @compass@ task, since we want the imports it creates in @_all.scss@ files to be processed by Compass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{% highlight js %}
// Project configuration.
grunt.initConfig({
    // Other config stuff not relevant to this example
    // ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;hljs undefined&quot;&gt;// Custom Task Configuration
'sass-directory-imports': {
    // This is an arbitrary name for this sub-task
    src: {
        files: {
            // Put an _all.scss file in any directory inside our scss files, and
            // this task will write @import statements for every other _*.scss
            // file in that directory. Then simply @import your _all.scss file to
            // import the contents of the directory.
            src: ['src/scss/**/_all.scss']
        }
    }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;});&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;// Load project tasks
grunt.loadTasks(&amp;#39;tasks&amp;#39;);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;// Default task(s).
grunt.registerTask(&amp;#39;default&amp;#39;, [&amp;#39;sass-directory-imports&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;compass&amp;#39;]);
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple but satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update, April 4:&lt;/em&gt; I added some needed improvements to the task, such as better logging (which can be turned off with the quiet option) and a fix for an out-and-out bug that cropped up when multiple files were found by the multi-task.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/searching-for-something-obvious-use-googles-im-feeling-lucky-in-chromes-omnibox</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/searching-for-something-obvious-use-googles-im-feeling-lucky-in-chromes-omnibox"/><title>Searching for something obvious? Use Google's I'm Feeling Lucky in Chrome's Omnibox</title><updated>Sat Apr 13 2013 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Looking up &amp;#39;php strftime&amp;#39; again? Skip a step by &amp;quot;adding a shortcut&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://productforums.google.com/forum/#!topic/chrome/ye0NLq9ANLc&quot;&gt;http://productforums.google.com/forum/#!topic/chrome/ye0NLq9ANLc&lt;/a&gt; to the first search result for Chrome&amp;#39;s omnibox. Then you can use a keyword like &amp;quot;l&amp;quot; to search for items that have obvious reference destinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus: Add a similar search engine with the keyword &amp;quot;m&amp;quot; to prefix your search with &amp;quot;mdn&amp;quot; so that the first result for JavaScript questions is from the Mozilla Developer Network instead of W3Schools.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/make-'exit'-detach-from-tmux-rather-than-close-a-window</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/make-'exit'-detach-from-tmux-rather-than-close-a-window"/><title>Make 'exit' detach from tmux rather than close a window</title><updated>Mon Apr 15 2013 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I use tmux (formerly screen - goodbye, old friend) to keep multiple workflows open on my VPS. Too frequently, I&amp;#39;ll come back to my terminal window after working on something else and type &amp;quot;exit&amp;quot; to log off. But, wait! I hadn&amp;#39;t detached from my tmux session. Instead of logging off, I killed one of my tmux windows, which is irritating because it represented something I wanted to keep open. And, because my fingers work faster than my brain, more often than not I&amp;#39;ll just type &amp;quot;exit&amp;quot; again before I realize why it didn&amp;#39;t work the first time. BAM. Now I have to try to put back together my tmux session when all I wanted to do was log off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to stop suffering this morning and wrote an exit function (placedin my .zshrc) that will either detatch if inside a tmux session, or exit like normal if not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{% highlight js %}
exit() {
    if [[ -z $TMUX ]]; then
        builtin exit
    else
        tmux detach
    fi
}
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It checks for &amp;quot;the presence of the $TMUX environment variable&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/10689/how-can-i-tell-if-im-in-a-tmux-session-from-a-bash-script&quot;&gt;http://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/10689/how-can-i-tell-if-im-in-a-tmux-session-from-a-bash-script&lt;/a&gt; (or, more accurately, checks &amp;quot;the length of the string $TMUX&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.elte.hu/zsh-manual/zsh_12.html)&quot;&gt;http://www.cs.elte.hu/zsh-manual/zsh_12.html)&lt;/a&gt;; if $TMUX is not set, it exits normally. Note the use of the builtin keyword, which references the original exit command rather than the function of the same name that this creates. If $TMUX is set, it detatches from the tmux session.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/save-directory-specific-ls-settings</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/save-directory-specific-ls-settings"/><title>Save directory-specific ls settings</title><updated>Wed May 01 2013 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;!(l-full){max-width:693px}/images/posts/custom-ls.png!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the nice things OS X does is retain way you sort individual directories. This helps the Downloads folder, in particular, which I always want sorted reverse chronologically by date modified so that I can see what I just downloaded at the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted my shell to do something similar: I changed my ls command to check for the existence of an @.lsrc@ file in the current directory. The @.lsrc@ file should be nothing but a set of arguments to be passed to the @ls@ command. For example, my @~/Downloads@ folder has this @.lsrc@:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{% highlight bash %}
-ltr
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;-l: use a long listing format&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;-t: sort by modification time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;-r: reverse order while sorting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I added this function to my @.zshrc@ file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{% highlight bash %}
ls() {
    if [[ -f ./.lsrc ]]; then
        /bin/ls &lt;code&gt;cat .lsrc&lt;/code&gt; $&lt;em&gt;
    else
        /bin/ls $&lt;/em&gt;
    fi
}
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The @ls@ command works normally everywhere else, but anywhere I want it to have specific default behavior, I just drop an @.lsrc@ file.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/game-review-yuan-zhou-on-kyu-cornucopia</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/game-review-yuan-zhou-on-kyu-cornucopia"/><title>Game Review: Yuan Zhou on Kyu Cornucopia</title><updated>Wed May 08 2013 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the strange aspects of being a student of Yuan Zhou is that I get to see &amp;quot;my games show up every so often in the American Go Association newsletter&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/members-edition-yuan-zhou-on-kyu-cornucopia/&quot;&gt;http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/05/members-edition-yuan-zhou-on-kyu-cornucopia/&lt;/a&gt;. These are games that we play in the afternoon during the monthly group go lessons. They&amp;#39;re tournament-style games, with 45 minutes on the clock for each player, and they&amp;#39;re handicapped according to our class &lt;a href=&quot;http://xyzgoclub.com&quot;&gt;ladder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all the games our finished, he reviews each one, which is a fantastic way to learn. Not only to I get to hear detailed feedback on my own moves and the moves of other players of similar ability, I get to ask questions immediately about points I don&amp;#39;t understand or other possibilities about which I&amp;#39;m curious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular game was against a player who is ahead of me on the ladder and against whom I was one and one, though with a reverse komi each time. (Instead of adding handicap stones, we award reverse komis so that the game flows more like an even game.) I don&amp;#39;t find his style to be intimidating, but he has a way of whittling away at me with more accurate reading. This game I fell behind due to too-typical mistakes, but was able to come back later by cutting off one of his groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you&amp;#39;ll enjoy my teacher&amp;#39;s comments; big thanks to Bill Cobb and Myron Souris for creating the game record. In the game record, the players are anonymized, but I hereby confess to playing black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eidogo-player-auto&quot; sgf=&quot;/sgf/2013_05_07_anonymous_kyus_yuanzhou.sgf&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/workshop-game-against-a-new-little-brother</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/workshop-game-against-a-new-little-brother"/><title>Workshop game against a new little brother</title><updated>Mon Jun 10 2013 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;!(l-full){max-width:456px}/images/posts/2013-06-09.jpg!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shifu announced on Sunday that we had a new little brother named Nathan who would be joining us who had just gone 5-0 at the Maryland open in the 4-6 kyu divison. (In Shifu&amp;#39;s group, all students are brothers and sisters: anyone who became a student before you is your older brother or sister, anyone who became a student after you is your little brother or sister.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happily, I was matched up against him in the afternoon. Shifu and Gurujeet said he liked to fight, which is great. Some of my best opponents (Diego, Ben) have fighting styles, and I looked forward to an exciting game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to make it an AGA ranked game, which meant it would be handicapped according to our official AGA ranks, even though neither is accurate. His is 5k, but he just went 5-0. Mine is 6k, but that&amp;#39;s because I haven&amp;#39;t been to a tournament in a year and a half. So Nathan played white with only a half-point komi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, after all of the games were finished, Shifu reviewed them with us. This record is constructed largely of my memory of Shifu&amp;#39;s comments, but also contains some of my own thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eidogo-player-auto&quot; sgf=&quot;/sgf/2013-06-09.sgf&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nathan and I recorded the game after it was finished entirely from memory, which is surprisingly easy to do at this point when working with my opponent. (Nathan, who has presumably not practiced remembering games this way as much, was already great at it.) I remember when the idea of remembering a whole game afterward seemed mind-boggling. I was happy if I could get past move 12 when I started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This marks my fifth win in a row at the group go lesson: I must say that it&amp;#39;s always a lot more pleasant to drive the hour it takes to get back to DC with a win under my belt than it is when there&amp;#39;s a loss sitting like a weight in my stomach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nathan said he hopes to come back next month, which would be great. I love the lessons at Shifu&amp;#39;s home, and my fellow students are a big part of what makes them worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/building-an-sgf-viewer-from-scratch</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/building-an-sgf-viewer-from-scratch"/><title>GoKibitz: Building an SGF viewer from scratch</title><updated>Mon Jun 17 2013 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the best things about go is that there&amp;#39;s so much to analyze and talk about outside of playing actual games. One of my favorite things is to look at games with comments on them, either pro games with commentary from strong players (like those at &amp;quot;Go Game Guru&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://gogameguru.com/)&quot;&gt;http://gogameguru.com/)&lt;/a&gt;, amateur games with commentary from teachers (like &amp;quot;those from my teacher&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://zhouyuan.com/teachingsample.html&quot;&gt;http://zhouyuan.com/teachingsample.html&lt;/a&gt;, Yuan Zhou), or games by players around my strength working through the same kinds of issues I am, like my longtime friend and go rival, &amp;quot;Ben Hong&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://bengozen.com/&quot;&gt;http://bengozen.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best option out there right now for displaying game records on a webpage is &amp;quot;Eidogo&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://eidogo.com/&quot;&gt;http://eidogo.com/&lt;/a&gt;, created by Justin Kramer. I can&amp;#39;t say enough in praise of Kramer&amp;#39;s work: it&amp;#39;s JavaScript-driven and the primary renderer is html and css. It does a lot more than display game records; its joseki tutor and pro game pattern search are remarkable. More than that, Kramer&amp;#39;s source code is clean, well-formatted, and well-commented. It&amp;#39;s a pleasure to browse through his JavaScript on Github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Eidogo lacks some things I&amp;#39;d really like out of an SGF viewer. It doesn&amp;#39;t respond to the width of the container it&amp;#39;s placed in, which means it doesn&amp;#39;t always look great on mobile devices, and it&amp;#39;s almost always in its narrow form when embedded on sites, which leaves too small an area for extended comments, in my opinion. Then there&amp;#39;s the feature I want most of all: the ability to allow others to comment on individual moves. You can usually comment on the post that a game in is embedded in, but that forces awkward descriptions like, &amp;quot;That extension in move 56 seems slow for white...&amp;quot; I&amp;#39;d like to allow discussions to arise around the moves themselves, as if readers were able to asynchronously join in a review of the game itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t blame Eidogo for any of this: Kramer developed Eidogo years ago, and with his own priorities. But it led me to try to create my own. I put off the project after a couple aborted starts: I&amp;#39;m not the programmer Kramer is, and I got stuck just writing a parser to translate SGF files (a text format created by &amp;quot;Anders Kierulf&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smartgo.com/anders.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.smartgo.com/anders.htm&lt;/a&gt;) into JavaScript. But the wonderful thing about my job is that I get paid to learn more about programming, so when I sat down recently to &amp;quot;try my luck again&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/neagle/gokibitz/blob/master/src/js/sgf.js&quot;&gt;https://github.com/neagle/gokibitz/blob/master/src/js/sgf.js&lt;/a&gt;, I found the task more approachable than I had before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I may as well go ahead and announce the start of &amp;quot;GoKibitz&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://gokibitz.com&quot;&gt;http://gokibitz.com&lt;/a&gt;, which is beginning life as an SGF viewer, but will hopefully grow to be an editor and more. I&amp;#39;ve got a very basic demo up, which you can view below. It only really works in Chrome right now. I have no intention of supporting older browsers, but it will eventually work correctly in Firefox and other modern browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s got some animation, which shows a bit of the direction I want to take the renderer, but the renderer itself is pretty half-baked right now. The logic for rendering is separate from everything else, and it&amp;#39;s the part I&amp;#39;ve spent the least time on. (I just wanted to create something to actually see stones to help keep myself motivated.) I&amp;#39;m probably going to move to something like &amp;quot;Paper JS&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://paperjs.org/&quot;&gt;http://paperjs.org/&lt;/a&gt; for rendering so that I can do more creative things with how the board, stones, and animations look. My dream is to have GoKibitz feel a little bit more like games from &amp;quot;Hikaru no Go&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hulu.com/hikaru-no-go&quot;&gt;http://www.hulu.com/hikaru-no-go&lt;/a&gt;, which used glowing stones, dramatic perspectives, and lots of other techniques to convey the drama of a game of go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, of course, at some point I&amp;#39;ll have to figure out how I want to enable per-move commenting. Do hook into a service like Disqus? Do I create my own API, powered by my own DB? Obviously there&amp;#39;s tons of work left to be done. As the proud father of a nearly one-year-old boy, I don&amp;#39;t have tons of time, either. But I&amp;#39;m enjoying myself so far, and I think that there are a decent amount of people who&amp;#39;d really appreciate a more dynamic way of showing and interacting with go games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy the demo (&amp;quot;direct link&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://gokibitz.com/demos/2013-06-15/&quot;&gt;http://gokibitz.com/demos/2013-06-15/&lt;/a&gt;) and, if you&amp;#39;re code-inclined, feel free to check out &amp;quot;the source&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/neagle/gokibitz/tree/master/src/js&quot;&gt;https://github.com/neagle/gokibitz/tree/master/src/js&lt;/a&gt;. You can also &amp;quot;follow the project on Twitter&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gokibitz&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/gokibitz&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://gokibitz.com/demos/2013-06-15/&quot; width=&quot;515&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; style=&quot;border: 5px solid #555;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/things-to-avoid-when-giving-presentations</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/things-to-avoid-when-giving-presentations"/><title>Things to avoid when giving presentations</title><updated>Fri Aug 09 2013 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Due to the gracious patronage of AOL, I had the privilege of attending the recent &amp;quot;An Event Apart&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://aneventapart.com/event/washington-dc-2013&quot;&gt;http://aneventapart.com/event/washington-dc-2013&lt;/a&gt; in DC. Overall, it was an outstanding event, and I was really glad I was able to attend. But it also made me think about some things that you should definitely not do in presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;h3. 1. Ask rhetorical questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;#39;t actually need an answer from the audience, don&amp;#39;t insult them by asking them. And &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; don&amp;#39;t ask them to raise their hands if you don&amp;#39;t really care. &amp;quot;Anybody out there a fan of... ADOBE PRODUCTS?&amp;quot; is an example of something you should not ask. &amp;quot;Raise your hand if you&amp;#39;ve ever asked this question in a client meeting...&amp;quot; I don&amp;#39;t need to raise my hand. Just tell me what you were going to tell me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s an example of an okay question: &amp;quot;How many people have tried out the new service from AnonymousServiceProvider? Ach, so few of you! Well, let me try to change that.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That seems like you actually care. A little bit. But asking rhetorical questions just to make me feel involved just makes me feel angry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;h3. 2. Provide links to gists in your slides&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Github gists are awesome in many ways. But here&amp;#39;s an example of what a link to one looks like: @&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/neagle/1367fef38c6b0d08c985@&quot;&gt;https://gist.github.com/neagle/1367fef38c6b0d08c985@&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great thing for putting in posts/Tweets/IMs/emails, because what it does really well is &lt;em&gt;go to something when it&amp;#39;s clicked on&lt;/em&gt;. What it does really poorly is spend any time in the human brain. I understand the desire to have references in one&amp;#39;s slides, but if you&amp;#39;re going to have URLs at all (which is questionable), make them human-readable shortlinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@&lt;a href=&quot;http://short.link/my-awesome-demo@&quot;&gt;http://short.link/my-awesome-demo@&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps even better: @Google: nate eagle awesome demo@&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But probably these things don&amp;#39;t need to be in your slides at all. Have a separate version of your slides available for people to check out later that does have links. Or provide audience members with a separate reference page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;h3. 3. Juice up your content with enthusiasm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your content should make me feel enthusiastic. Your enthusiasm will not make me like your content. If you&amp;#39;re way out in front of your content, your enthusiasm will make me suspicious and annoyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me put it a different way: show me that something is awesome by showing me awesome things. And, yes, you can speak about it with energy and enthusiasm. But when you show me something and then try to &lt;em&gt;tell&lt;/em&gt; me it&amp;#39;s awesome with your tone and diction, I just get irritated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: this is very poor advice for dealing with people other than me, since the reaction on Twitter to one of the talks delivered this way seemed overwhelmingly positive. But I didn&amp;#39;t like it a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;h3. 4. Have a lame central metaphor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Central metaphors should be good, or not used. If they&amp;#39;re nothing but a vague story wrapper for asking why more often, they&amp;#39;re just weighing your presentation down. Strip it out and talk about something interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/tons-of-work-to-create-something-incredibly-lame</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/tons-of-work-to-create-something-incredibly-lame"/><title>Tons of work to create something incredibly lame</title><updated>Fri Aug 09 2013 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A while ago, I contributed some money to the interesting &amp;quot;Play More Go!&amp;quot; campaign. They&amp;#39;ve released the second of the promotional spots, and I&amp;#39;m sad to say that not only aren&amp;#39;t they something I want to put out there to show people what&amp;#39;s interesting about go, I find them a little embarrassing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Important note: I&amp;#39;m a bit embarrassed to be complaining about this at all. You know how much effort and enterprise it took to make these things? You know how much effort and enterprise I&amp;#39;ve shown in &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; my entire life? But I&amp;#39;m doing it anyway because I&amp;#39;m an asshole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&amp;#39;re shockingly generic and if I had to sum up what they&amp;#39;ve communicated so far about go, it&amp;#39;d be: &amp;quot;Go. Cool, I guess? Fun to do while drinking wine?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stories seem like they were created by someone who had &amp;quot;Go: cool / fun&amp;quot; written on a yellow index card, actually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it depresses me, not because it&amp;#39;s so horrible to fail at something very difficult (you want _me_ to write a better promo spot? umm, er...) but because it&amp;#39;s depressing how completely dependent all of the work of hiring actors, lighting sets, recording, and editing is on a &lt;em&gt;good script&lt;/em&gt;. When I watch bad animated movies, for instance, my heart almost stops when I imagine the tens of thousands of man hours that were tossed down the hole of a half-baked, patronizing script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough complaining. If you haven&amp;#39;t seen them already, check out the two spots and let me know what you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;More than a Game - Play More Go!&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RVbGgla-FZE&quot;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RVbGgla-FZE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/RVbGgla-FZE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;What is it About? - Play More Go!&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=doX5kKAgXk8&quot;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=doX5kKAgXk8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/doX5kKAgXk8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;h2. Update&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in a comment on this post, I showed these to my wife and she loved them. There are few people whose taste I share as much as I do hers, so I found this jarring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find many more comments on these videos on &amp;quot;this post over at GoGameGuru&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://gogameguru.com/the-game-of-go-what-is-it/#comments&quot;&gt;http://gogameguru.com/the-game-of-go-what-is-it/#comments&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/go-weekend-at-diegos</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/go-weekend-at-diegos"/><title>Go Weekend at Diego's</title><updated>Mon Nov 18 2013 00:00:00 GMT-0500 (EST)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;!(l-full){max-width:960px}/images/posts/nate-vs-sam.jpg!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend my parents-in-law Mark and Vickie traveled up from Charlottesville to watch my son so that I could travel down to Virginia Beach to spend the weekend at my little brother &amp;quot;Diego&amp;#39;s&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DiegoArgus&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/DiegoArgus&lt;/a&gt; house playing go. (We are both students of &amp;quot;Yuan Zhou&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://zhouyuan.com/&quot;&gt;http://zhouyuan.com/&lt;/a&gt;, which makes us brothers. Any student who began before me is my older sibling, any student who began after me is my younger sibling.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diego and I are very close in strength, but with different styles. We&amp;#39;ve played many games over the last two years and we take lessons together every two weeks via Skype / &amp;quot;KGS&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://gokgs.com&quot;&gt;http://gokgs.com&lt;/a&gt; with Shifu, so we know each other&amp;#39;s go very well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Diego has to drive almost three hours up to Germandtown, Maryland every month to attend our group lessons, we decided to have a road trip down to his house near Virginia Beach to play as much go as we could fit into two days with him and three of his colleagues, who are all of similar strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Ben&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://bengozen.com&quot;&gt;http://bengozen.com&lt;/a&gt; ended up having to stay home due to sickness, but I drove down Saturday morning in my little yellow Beetle. Since I drive to and from work every day with my sixteen-month-old son, whose daycare is right next to my workplace, it&amp;#39;s always strange for me to get in the car without him. But the drive was beautiful. The weather was mild and gray, like it is in Washington State, where I spent my teenage years. I thought a lot about how deep the satisfaction of playing go was. Its age, simplicity, and beauty give it a purpose and value unto itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a story about a farmer who was traveling in the woods near his village one day. He came across two old men playing go and he stopped for a while to watch them play. Soon he became absorbed in the game and was startled when one of the players looked up and suggested that it might be time for him to go home. He walked slowly back to his village, still thinking about the game, but when he arrived found that he had not been gone for an afternoon, but for decades, and that everyone he knew had grown old. Go games reach toward timelessness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!(l-full){max-width:1024px}/images/posts/diegos-go-room.jpg!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diego welcomed me to his home and showed me the sun room where he had his kaya (!) goban set up with a set of snow grade (!!) slate and shell stones. Diego&amp;#39;s wife treated us to delicious toasted roast beef and pepperjack sandwiches for lunch, after which Diego&amp;#39;s colleagues Sam, Zhaoyan, and Hyung arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using our iPhones as game clocks, we proceeded to play three rounds with 45 minutes per player on the clock and five byo-yomi periods of 30 seconds. My first opponent was Sam. He has an aggressive style and will frequently invade strong positions, challenging his opponents to prove that they really ought to get territory they might have thought they already had. Our game ended in a big fight in which I captured a large group, but there was plenty of back and forth until then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My second match was against Zhaoyan, who hasn&amp;#39;t been beaten, yet, in Diego&amp;#39;s company and I would not prove the first to beat him. We were able to partially reconstruct a record from that game; sadly, it is more than enough to show the differences in our strengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eidogo-player-auto&quot; sgf=&quot;/sgf/2013-11-16-nate-vs-zhaoyan.sgf&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My third match was against Hyung, and I was able to win in the end. Diego recorded the game while we played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eidogo-player-auto&quot; sgf=&quot;/sgf/2013-11-16-nate-vs-hyung.sgf&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sam and Zhaoyan went home and Hyung stayed for a while, during which time we ordered pizza and Diego treated me to a carefully crafted martini. We talked a lot about great Go players like Lee Chang Ho, Lee Sedol, Takemiya Masaki, Kitani Minoru, and more. And Hyung related the same story I told above about the farmer and the go game. It was pretty great: that&amp;#39;s my idea of good conversation to have while drinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diego and Hyung played a game that I recorded, though I caught myself falling asleep on several occasions. It was a riviting game, but I&amp;#39;d woken up with my son at 5:50 AM, and that martini was doing a number on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterward, Diego and I played a final game for the day. It had been months since we played. Nigiri for color: Diego got black. And he had the audacity to play the mini-Chinese opening, which is &lt;em&gt;kind of my thing&lt;/em&gt;. Well: I shouldn&amp;#39;t say it&amp;#39;s my thing, because the game proved that I do not understand it well enough to counter it. Diego developed a tremendous amount of territory in the corner &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; along the side. I tried to counter with a large central moyo, not a strategy at which I&amp;#39;m particularly talented. I tried my best to edge the game closer and closer, but at last I got too desperate, overreached, and Diego cut apart a group on the side and I resigned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was too tired and battered after that game to try to make a record of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed a comfortable night&amp;#39;s sleep and woke up (after sleeping late! parents know where I&amp;#39;m coming from) to breakfast and a fresh pot of coffee. Diego and I played another game of go, switching colors. This time I was able to win, which made it a little easier to hold my head up. Diego and I watched a lecture on breaking the bamboo (a fighting technique) from the &amp;quot;Yunusseng Dojang&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://yunguseng.com/&quot;&gt;http://yunguseng.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At lunch, we were rejoined by Sam and Zhaoyan. Zhaoyan and I played again while Diego played Sam. This time I did better: I focused on choosing straightforward joseki that would make it harder for me to make a mistake allowing him to develop a large position. I also played black, which made it a little easier. Despite getting an inferior result out of the &amp;quot;taisha joseki&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://senseis.xmp.net/?TaishaJoseki&quot;&gt;http://senseis.xmp.net/?TaishaJoseki&lt;/a&gt;, which I worked on in my most recent lesson with Shifu and still managed to bungle, I thought that black came out ahead in the opening and most of the middle game. My only liability was a large group in the center made up of a pyramid of &amp;quot;monkey faces&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://senseis.xmp.net/?SakeBottleShape&quot;&gt;http://senseis.xmp.net/?SakeBottleShape&lt;/a&gt; which I thought was taken care of. But in the late middle game, Zhaoyan found a weak spot and cut. I wasn&amp;#39;t far enough ahead that I could give up one part of the group, so I fought for life. It was an interesting fight, but Zhaoyan played calmly, carefully, and left me with nothing. I resigned, all hopes of being the first to defeat Zhaoyan dashed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My final game was against Sam, and, true to form, it turned into a big, fierce battle after a deep invasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eidogo-player-auto&quot; sgf=&quot;/sgf/2013-11-17-nate-vs-sam.sgf&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sam played the &amp;quot;sanrensei&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://senseis.xmp.net/?SanrenseiFuseki&quot;&gt;http://senseis.xmp.net/?SanrenseiFuseki&lt;/a&gt;, which I have a harder time dealing with than I think I should. After two approaches and two pincers, black had given me center influence while taking territory, but I had almost nothing &lt;em&gt;but&lt;/em&gt; influence. Luckily for me, Sam invaded deep and gave me a target, making that influence useful, and I was able to win in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And before I knew it, it was time to drive home. I&amp;#39;d played seven intense, timed games over two days. I was exhausted and happy, ready to see my wife and son again. I headed home, my mind filled with go.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/friendship-games-2013</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/friendship-games-2013"/><title>Friendship Games 2013</title><updated>Tue Dec 10 2013 00:00:00 GMT-0500 (EST)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My teacher, &amp;quot;Yuan Zhou&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://zhouyuan.com&quot;&gt;http://zhouyuan.com&lt;/a&gt;, goes down to the &amp;quot;Triangle Go Club&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trianglegoclub.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.trianglegoclub.org/&lt;/a&gt; on occasion to do workshops. This year, he had attendees play remote games against his students via KGS. They played in front of physical boards and Shifu (Yuan) played their moves for us on KGS, then played our moves for them on the boards. I suspect that the process was more laborious than Shifu anticipated, because the games ended up taking a long time, despite having standard time settings of 45 minutes per side with five byo-yomi periods of 30 seconds each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I played someone I hadn&amp;#39;t met, but my opponent was white and Shifu said it was a no-komi game, which means white should be about a stone stronger than me. And, indeed, it turned out to be a grueling, difficult game that lasted over four hours. The yose (end game) was extremely close, but I think I was a little bit behind. Fortunately, white missed a weakness at the very end and I was able to capture a group, prompting white&amp;#39;s resignation. Still, I was frustrated because my judgment and counting turned out to be wrong. Earlier in the game, I thought black was in a better position than it actually was, and even at the end of the game, when I realized things were very close, I thought black had a slight lead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eidogo-player-auto&quot; sgf=&quot;/sgf/2013-12-06-nate-vs-dave.sgf&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/nine-stones</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/nine-stones"/><title>Nine Stones</title><updated>Tue Dec 10 2013 00:00:00 GMT-0500 (EST)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I scratch my head and frown at the board.
I sniff air through my nostrils like a bull.
I place a stone next to the white invader
and the print of my finger glistens wetly.
&amp;quot;That&amp;#39;s why they make the weaker player
play black in handicap games,&amp;quot;
someone once joked. &amp;quot;So you can see them sweat.&amp;quot;
My opponent, who has been running his fingers
through the stones in his bowl, making them
clack, immediately places another stone next to mine.
&amp;quot;That was,&amp;quot; he says slowly, &amp;quot;Not correct.&amp;quot;
I clench my teeth and wonder
how much the sudden flush to my neck and ears shows.
I was given nine stones, a nine-stone head start.
Nine stones scattered over a whole board
as if I owned it all already.
Nine stones, marking each of the star points
a sign that your opponent can give you
everything
because you know how to keep nothing.
I look at the now-cut-off cluster of black stones -
a broken dragon, a clump of bones and flesh
tangled and ugly
and now dead, dead, dead -
and try to judge whether I&amp;#39;m so behind
that the polite thing would be to resign.
But I can&amp;#39;t tell.
So, I decide
to struggle.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/six-stones-vs-shifu</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/six-stones-vs-shifu"/><title>Six stones vs. Shifu</title><updated>Thu Jan 09 2014 00:00:00 GMT-0500 (EST)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;eidogo-player-auto&quot; sgf=&quot;/sgf/20140109115231_jaguar_vs_cloudbrows.sgf&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take lessons every two weeks from &amp;quot;Yuan Zhou&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://zhouyuan.com&quot;&gt;http://zhouyuan.com&lt;/a&gt; via Skype and &amp;quot;KGS&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://gokgs.org&quot;&gt;http://gokgs.org&lt;/a&gt;. Every so often, he&amp;#39;ll play a simul game against Diego and me in which we have six handicap stones with free placement. Free placement is an astonishing advantage with handicap stones, allowing you to form your own structures rather than the standard star-point placement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the second or third time, I formed two shimari and then played hoshi (the star point) in the remaining two corners. If I, playing white, looked out at a board like that before my first move, I might break down crying. But not only did I fail to beat Shifu (as I have always failed), I failed to make it close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fought as fiercely as I could. Frankly, I enjoy facing Shifu, because the game is all combat, and I like to imagine myself baring my fangs, forcing my teacher to cut me down. Watching how white handles this game is beautiful; white is constantly leaning, pressing one direction in order to build the strength to slash in the other direction. All he needs is one target, and with that target he creates more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think there were some changes this game, but it&amp;#39;s depressing how quickly I got pressed into survival mode, as my potential for territory dried up in front of my eyes. But I think games like this are great practice: I spent almost two hours reading intensely, worrying about the pure elements of the midgame: connections, eye shape, and positional judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someday I&amp;#39;ll beat him.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/half-point-loss</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/half-point-loss"/><title>Half-Point Loss</title><updated>Fri Jan 17 2014 00:00:00 GMT-0500 (EST)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;eidogo-player-auto&quot; sgf=&quot;/sgf/2013_12-15_xxx_anonymous-kyus_yuanzhou.sgf&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
At December&amp;#39;s group lesson, I played Nathan for the fourth time. I was up two games to one, at the time. We did nigiri for color, which Nathan won; he chose white. I asked, curious, &amp;quot;Do you always prefer white?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Well,&amp;quot; he said, &amp;quot;Not with only 6.5 komi,&amp;quot; -- which is the standard compensation for white, who plays second, by Japanese rules -- &amp;quot;But when it gets to 7.5 komi,&amp;quot; -- which is the compensation according to &amp;quot;American Go Association&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://usgo.org&quot;&gt;http://usgo.org&lt;/a&gt; rules -- &amp;quot;I feel better off with white.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was happy to let him take white; most players prefer black despite the compensation white gets with the komi. As black, it&amp;#39;s easier to set the agenda for the game, following your own plan. But I find the notion of preferring white appealing: if you&amp;#39;re good at ruining your opponent&amp;#39;s plan and breaking the game up into a lot of small fights, having that komi can seem awfully appealing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought I had won this game, though I was worried that it was closer than I realized. I was in byo-yomi by the final third of the game, so I didn&amp;#39;t have a chance to count after the middle game. I was dismayed to find that I&amp;#39;d lost by 0.5 points. And in go, it just doesn&amp;#39;t matter what the margin of victory is: the winner by half a point takes it all. Nathan&amp;#39;s foresight proved accurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It showed that I still have a hard time not over-valuing captured stones: because of the white stones I captured on the bottom, I just had this &lt;em&gt;feeling&lt;/em&gt; that I had more points than I really had. It&amp;#39;s an instinct I need to overcome by counting more and assuming less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Bill Cobb and Myron Souris for the game record, which they created from &amp;quot;Yuan Zhou&amp;#39;s&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://zhouyuan.com&quot;&gt;http://zhouyuan.com&lt;/a&gt; review after our game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s hard for me to get too down about this game since Nathan came back and beat me by resignation in January, taking the lead against me with three wins to my two. It shows I have bigger things than half a point to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I&amp;#39;m managing to hold steady at two kyu right now on KGS, which is amazing. I still have disturbingly weak parts of my game, but I&amp;#39;m getting more resilient, and more of my games are won or lost by smaller margins, which is a heartening sign of steadier play. If I can figure out how to be more disciplined about doing tsumego and life and death study this year, I think I could tap shodan level on KGS some time this year.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/game-review-nate-vs-matt</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/game-review-nate-vs-matt"/><title>Game Review: Nate vs. Matt</title><updated>Thu Feb 06 2014 00:00:00 GMT-0500 (EST)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a game I played recently against my younger brother, Matt. (All fellow students of my teacher, &amp;quot;Yuan Zhou&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://zhouyuan.com&quot;&gt;http://zhouyuan.com&lt;/a&gt;, are my siblings. Students who preceded me are &amp;quot;older&amp;quot; and students who came after me are &amp;quot;younger&amp;quot;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met Matt at &amp;quot;the 2011 Maryland Open&amp;quot;:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usgo.org/news/2011/06/ke-huang-7d-wins-2011-maryland-open/&quot;&gt;http://www.usgo.org/news/2011/06/ke-huang-7d-wins-2011-maryland-open/&lt;/a&gt; over a go board; I was 10k and he was 11k. Matt and I talked after our game and I told him about taking lessons; he became a student himself shortly afterward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m proud of the progress I&amp;#39;ve made since 2011, but Matt proved in this game that he&amp;#39;s made dramatic progress, too. This was a no-komi game where I played white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Matt and I went over this game with Shifu (Yuan Zhou) in our individual lessons. These comments are my attempt to preserve some of the things that came out of my lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time there is a statement in quotation marks, I am quoting Shifu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(These opening and closing remarks are reproduced in the game record so that it makes sense independent of this post.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/jaguar-nate-vs-matt.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eidogo-player-auto&quot; sgf=&quot;/sgf/jaguar-nate-vs-matt.sgf&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Correct judgment in the opening is very important, particularly when both players are playing calmly and waiting for the appropriate moment to begin fighting. Making a move that doesn&amp;#39;t work well with your other stones can leave you at an immediate disadvantage. That&amp;#39;s one reason some styles emphasize initiating fighting as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes my fighting is too lax, too patient. I had an opportunity early to cleanly kill black&amp;#39;s stones with a peep and a seal, but I didn&amp;#39;t look hard enough for it because I was content to play an obvious but slack move. If I&amp;#39;m going to play for thickness, I need to recognize that when I&amp;#39;ve got my chance, I have to attack as sharply as possible. &amp;quot;When it&amp;#39;s time to shoot, shoot! Don&amp;#39;t talk!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Never help your opponent! My peep in the upper left gave black a key stone. Never assume a forcing move is free. If your opponent is going to win, make sure they win by taking things from you: no presents allowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Study life and death. Life and death isn&amp;#39;t just an abstract pursuit: if I had handled the top correctly, it would have been game over. My L&amp;amp;D skills are lagging behind the rest of my game right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tsumego study matters. Because of my tsumego study, I accurately and easily identified one tesuji, but I missed a simple net. Those kinds of nets are maybe 12k level - continuing to do many relatively quick, easy problems will help me avoid mistakes like this. Because of this, I lost another opportunity to win the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thickness has value! I made tons of mistakes in this game, but managed to win in the end because playing thick gave me so many opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/falling-to-pieces</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/falling-to-pieces"/><title>Falling To Pieces</title><updated>Sun Apr 20 2014 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;#39;ve been feeling the stirrings of ambition to get some personal projects done. For much of the past twenty-two months, I&amp;#39;ve mostly worked on surviving. Twenty-two months ago my son was born, and my activities were immediately reduced to only the top few on my priority list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taking care of my son.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working for a living.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Playing go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s not that I don&amp;#39;t have time for anything else: I have a little bit of time at the end of the day, usually. But I don&amp;#39;t have the energy. 9:30 rolls around, my son is finally asleep, and I&amp;#39;m fit for little more than rewatching a 30 Rock episode or two and falling asleep on the couch. I&amp;#39;ve been very lucky in terms of go, because I have a two-hour private lesson every two weeks, and an all-day group lesson one Sunday every month. My wife has generously gone out of her way to make sure I can keep doing my lessons. As a result, I&amp;#39;ve gotten stronger at a steady pace over the last two years: at the 2012 New Jersey Open, I went 3-2 as a 6 kyu, and at the 2014 New Jersey Open, I went 3-2 as a 2 kyu. Two stones a year is better than I deserve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;#39;s been hard to get anything else of any kind done, not even the project I care most about, &lt;a href=&quot;http://gokibitz.com&quot;&gt;Go Kibitz&lt;/a&gt;, a SGF player and editor I began almost a year go. Again: it&amp;#39;s not that I lack the time. If I jumped to my feet the moment my boy was asleep, grabbed my computer, and got to work, I could probably fit in about two hours of work a night. If I were the kind of person who could get by on six hours of sleep, I could fit in four hours. Some people do that, you know: they write books, they get graduate degrees, they make whole video games. I hate those people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But getting back to where we started: recently I&amp;#39;ve wanted to try to get some motion going again on some of my personal projects. But everything I want to do seems to lead to something else, and so many of the things I want to do involve learning non-trivial things I don&amp;#39;t already know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want to get GoKibitz back in action. It was really close to being a usable project!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well, sure, but you still didn&amp;#39;t have a way to do the main thing you wanted it for: to let people add comments to SGF files. To do that, you need to set up a DB - something like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mongodb.org/&quot;&gt;Mongo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good point: maybe I should set up Mongo. Of course, then I have to worry about setting up authorization if I&amp;#39;m going to write an API for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking of APIs, you&amp;#39;re going to have to actually learn &lt;a href=&quot;http://expressjs.com/&quot;&gt;Express&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That shouldn&amp;#39;t be too difficult. Aren&amp;#39;t they bundling that together these days with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mean.io/&quot;&gt;MEAN stack&lt;/a&gt;? And you&amp;#39;ve wanted to learn &lt;a href=&quot;https://angularjs.org/&quot;&gt;Angular JS&lt;/a&gt;, too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perfect! There&amp;#39;s even &lt;a href=&quot;http://addyosmani.com/blog/full-stack-javascript-with-mean-and-yeoman/&quot;&gt;a yeoman generator&lt;/a&gt; for the MEAN Stack. Add an item to my to-do list: make an app with the MEAN stack!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aaugaugughghghghgh. I can&amp;#39;t even figure out how to add a new page to this stupid app. Learning Express, Mongo, and Angular together is failing hard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You know what? Screw this app. I&amp;#39;ll just work on GoKibitz again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Though, I should really write a new renderer for it... the old one was in HTML/CSS, which looked pretty, but was limited. I should be using something like &lt;a href=&quot;http://paperjs.org/&quot;&gt;PaperJS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But is PaperJS really the best framework to use? Why don&amp;#39;t I try making something in it and WebGL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://threejs.org/&quot;&gt;three.js&lt;/a&gt; looks like a fantastic framework for WebGL - hmm, and I should be able to make a stone-shaped disc pretty easily. Just have to read up on custom shape generators.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is going to take a while. Maybe I should just work on blogging a little more about go while I&amp;#39;m doing this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aw, shit: I haven&amp;#39;t upgraded the version of Ubuntu my VPS is running on in ages and now the upgrade script keeps failing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time to set up a new disk image and migrate everything from my old one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But now I can&amp;#39;t generate my blog, because Jekyll has different requirements now. Should I fix my site?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No! Times have changed. For one thing, Jekyll&amp;#39;s liquid templates suck. I&amp;#39;m way more familiar with Node JS than I was when I set this blog up; I should pick a Node JS static site generator. &lt;a href=&quot;http://wintersmith.io/&quot;&gt;Wintersmith&lt;/a&gt; looks good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You know, why go to the trouble of learning somebody else&amp;#39;s system? How complicated is a static site generator? You should just write one yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now THAT&amp;#39;S a good idea. Let me just find a good model... &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wesleytodd/rufio&quot;&gt;Rufio&lt;/a&gt; looks promising.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Several hours in, I&amp;#39;m beginning to think Rufio is pretty much exactly what I want my static site generator to be. Why don&amp;#39;t I just use Rufio?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great: with that decided, isn&amp;#39;t it time to change the design of your homepage? It&amp;#39;s kinda weak sauce, and wouldn&amp;#39;t it be a good idea to focus more on go, since that&amp;#39;s what you want to write more about?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe: should I do that or should I turn my homepage into more of a landing portal with stuff about me that links to a separate, fully go-focused blog?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not a bad idea. But how do I want to design it? Do I want a design inspired by Howard Pyle, like my old blog? Do I want a more early- to mid-20th-century modern style? Why don&amp;#39;t I browse &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aisleone.net/&quot;&gt;Aisle One&lt;/a&gt; for inspiration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oh, I don&amp;#39;t know... it&amp;#39;s so hard to pick a design direction. Why don&amp;#39;t I download &lt;a href=&quot;http://macaw.co&quot;&gt;that new design program&lt;/a&gt; so that it&amp;#39;s easier to experiment?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Damn it: it&amp;#39;s going to take some time to get comfortable using this program. Why don&amp;#39;t I just go with a simple design?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why don&amp;#39;t I just pick up where I left off with GoKibitz?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pity anyone who took the time to actually read all of that. It&amp;#39;s nothing more than the shameful record of a mind utterly incapable of setting out to actually do a single thing. It left me, somewhere last week, having what may have amounted to an actual anxiety attack. My head was pounding, I couldn&amp;#39;t sit still, I was breathing heavily. So on the way home, I decided two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will fix my old blog - get an old version of Jekyll, whatever it takes. I will not update a single thing about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will break GoKibitz into pieces: the SGF parser, the game navigator, the renderer, etc. I will package them as NPM modules and I will work on them one at a time, not worrying about putting them together until later. The parser itself is worth making available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#39;ll start blogging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;#39;s it. And as soon as I post this, I&amp;#39;ll have done all three of those things. The blog is fixed (I did, indeed, have to install an old version of Jekyll) and I&amp;#39;ve released my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.org/package/smartgame&quot;&gt;SGF parser on NPM&lt;/a&gt;. I learned a lot in the course of putting together an NPM module: I set up my first mocha tests, I have the build passing through Travis CI, I wrote a method to turn parsed games back into SGFs, and I even found and discovered an important bug in the parser that had gone unnoticed before. Next up is writing a navigator for parsed SGF files that has an API for moving throughout a game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s not much, and even this much concerted effort has left me feeling pretty worn out, but it&amp;#39;s something.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/tintin-and-hadock-playing-go</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/tintin-and-hadock-playing-go"/><title>Tintin and Haddock Playing Go (English Translation)</title><updated>Fri May 02 2014 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite recent go discoveries on the web is &lt;a href=&quot;http://gogoigo.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;Go Go Igo!&lt;/a&gt;, a French Tumblr. It has a lot of game records from high-profile go matches, none of which I&amp;#39;ve ever opened, but it also has tons of go-related images from around the web. It doesn&amp;#39;t tend to have image sources, which is a shame, but the images themselves are great. Recently, they posted an image of page from &lt;em&gt;Tintin in Tibet&lt;/em&gt; showing Tintin and Haddock playing go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/tintin-haddock-go.jpg&quot; class=&quot;l-full&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 594px;&quot; alt=&quot;Tintin and Haddock Playing Go&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife is a huge Tintin fan and owns most of the books, so I&amp;#39;ve read them all at one point or another, too. I was pretty thrilled to discover that there was a go reference in &lt;em&gt;Tintin in Tibet&lt;/em&gt; (my wife&amp;#39;s favorite). Sadly, she quickly pulled out the book and showed me what the original panel looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/tintin-au-tibet.jpg&quot; class=&quot;l-full&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 576px;&quot; alt=&quot;Tintin and Haddock Playing... Chess!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chess?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s pretty embarrassing that I was so easily fooled (especially since the go version has the text in Comic Sans), but I guess it shows that one is always ready to believe what one wants to believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the reworked fan image is great, and I love the internal monologue the creator gave Haddock as he ponders the game&amp;#39;s position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a quick English translation, since the French is simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how could I get myself in such shit! And at six stones! Here, this is fucking... if I attack his moyo, I don&amp;#39;t make any points and he&amp;#39;ll chase me and I&amp;#39;m cooked, for sure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This shape, here, is it solid? And if I play here first, what does that do? I play there, he plays there, here... yeah, that seems good. Protect the san-san? It&amp;#39;s not very active... I have to play globally! Then here, along the side, but the third or the fourth line? Hm... and it&amp;#39;s not very sente. Playing there is for the end game, too small... here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...the cut there... hm, I have this threat to net here, and if he looks to get out here, I consolidate my position and make an enormous territory on this side and afterwards I can attack this damn moyo! Bravo! My dear Tintin, I ask you what will you say to this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone knows the original source for this image, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/progress-on-gokibitz</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/progress-on-gokibitz"/><title>Progress on GoKibitz</title><updated>Sun May 04 2014 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m going to take a break from work to write a little. I&amp;#39;m happy to report that I&amp;#39;ve had a productive weekend on my most important personal project, &lt;a href=&quot;http://gokibitz.com&quot;&gt;GoKibitz&lt;/a&gt;. For one thing, my compassionate wife read &lt;a href=&quot;/2014/04/20/falling-to-pieces/&quot;&gt;my post&lt;/a&gt; and has gone out of her way to make time for me to code when we&amp;#39;re both home with our son. For another, there&amp;#39;s been some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lifein19x19.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=10&amp;amp;t=10226&quot;&gt;recent conversation on go-related development&lt;/a&gt; at Life in 19x19 that&amp;#39;s ramped up my enthusiasm about getting some of the things I&amp;#39;ve worked on to a point that they could actually be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also put up &lt;a href=&quot;http://gokibitz.com/demos/2014-05-02/&quot;&gt;the last version of GoKibitz&lt;/a&gt; that I had been working on, and was pleasantly surprised by how much work I had done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I also found out about &lt;a href=&quot;http://wgo.waltheri.net/player&quot;&gt;WGo.js&lt;/a&gt;, an SGF Player by Jan Prokop. As you can see from &lt;a href=&quot;http://wgo.waltheri.net/demo/player/1&quot;&gt;the demo&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;#39;s got all the relevant features, but more importantly, it has a well-documented event system that will make it really easy to interact with. When I saw this, I thought, why the hell am I recreating all this? (Historical note: the origination of GoKibitz was my desire to add the ability for users viewing an embedded &lt;a href=&quot;http://eidogo.com/&quot;&gt;Eidogo&lt;/a&gt; player to add comments to individual move. When I found Eidigo too limited to do this easily, I decided to make my own player.) Why don&amp;#39;t I just work on creating an API for saving and retrieving comments?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do that, I had to finally figure out how to set up Express and MongoDB. These technologies should be really easy for me: I&amp;#39;ve worked with JavaScript for years. But I drown pretty easily when dropped into more complex, MVC-style structures. At work, I almost always work inside existing setups that involve adding features and modifying what&amp;#39;s already present; that&amp;#39;s not that difficult. But if things need to be reworked too much, I get out of my comfort zone quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That frustrates and embarrasses me, by the way. Even admitting how much of a problem these kinds of abstractions pose for me reveals what a hack I am as a developer. But I started coding in JS with jQuery in an extremely linear fashion. I treated it like CSS: select something, then do something with it. I could add a lot of functionality to pages that way, and I got hooked quickly on the pleasure of being able to add so much to the behavior layer of a page. I&amp;#39;ve learned a lot over the years since then, but I haven&amp;#39;t &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; designed applications more complicated than widgets from scratch. (I&amp;#39;ve worked inside plenty, without trouble.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But having blocks of time this weekend to focus helped me a lot: I worked my way through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codemag.com/Article/1210041&quot;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://scotch.io/tutorials/javascript/easy-node-authentication-setup-and-local&quot;&gt;excellent&lt;/a&gt; tutorials and now have a functioning app powered by Node + Express that lets a user create an account, upload SGFs, and provides an API for making, listing, viewing, updating, and deleting comments associated with a game and move number. (Next up: allowing users to add variations.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My brain is different: the Express setup really makes sense (though there will be plenty more to figure out about it). I got from wondering how in the hell routes worked at all to figuring out how to make successful logins redirect back to the original pages that redirected users away because of required authorization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only bad thing is that I haven&amp;#39;t played any go or done many problems in the last week, but it doesn&amp;#39;t matter. Advancing my development ability is at least as important as advancing my strength in go, and the thrill you get when you start to realize how much power Express gives you to develop your own applications is every bit as great as winning an important game in go.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/gulp-pattern-lint</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/gulp-pattern-lint"/><title>Gulp Pattern Lint</title><updated>Thu May 08 2014 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When Grunt came along, it really changed the way I set up all my projects as a front-end developer. Instead of sometimes having a Compass project or sometimes having a Jekyll project, everything became a Grunt project. Instead of relying on my own workflow for things like JSHint settings and text-editor preferences, I started setting up all those specifications on a project level. Rather than relying on globally installed ruby gems, I began relying on getting everything I needed for a project by typing &lt;code&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt; in a project&amp;#39;s directory. Instead of relying on someone else&amp;#39;s framework, I felt like I was assembling a different toolkit for each project, uniquely suited to the task at hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.artzstudio.com/&quot;&gt;Dave&lt;/a&gt; sidled up to me at work one day and said, &amp;quot;So, I think we should use Gulp instead of Grunt,&amp;quot; I didn&amp;#39;t react very well. I may have given him a dead-eyed stare and said, &amp;quot;What in the name of Thoth are you talking about?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;It uses streams!&amp;quot; Dave said. &amp;quot;And pipes!&amp;quot; I wasn&amp;#39;t impressed. Streams have to be forded, or you have to caulk the wagon and float across, and usually somebody in the party dies. And pipes are exclusively transportation for Mario brothers. But when my buddy &lt;a href=&quot;http://therouxdown.com/&quot;&gt;Andrew&lt;/a&gt; posted a comparison of one project&amp;#39;s Gruntfile vs. the new Gulpfile he&amp;#39;d made for it, I had to reluctantly concede that the Gulpfile was a lot easier to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strongest reason I saw for trying Gulp was its emphasis on code rather than config. In Grunt, you set up a giant config object, full of tasks and options and file lists and destinations. Any time you have configuration, you have code operating behind the scenes to determine what to do with that configuration. Which means you&amp;#39;ve got to learn about that code&amp;#39;s rules and practices in order to use the configuration properly. And even a year and a half into using Grunt, I still spent a certain amount of time with new projects banging my head against the configuration when it didn&amp;#39;t work the way I expected it to. But Gulp used straight JavaScript to make tasks with a chain of plugins that source files passed through to get to their destination. In Grunt, where I had a config object full of tools (concat, copy, sass, etc) that I told what to do, in Gulp I took a set of files, then passed them through the relevant tools, then put them where I wanted them. Another nice thing about the Gulp approach is that I didn&amp;#39;t have to write the files somewhere after each tool did what it needed to: they could all modify the file as a stream, then pass that stream on. I only wrote the files at the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, fortunately and unfortunately, I abandoned Grunt. I&amp;#39;m pretty sad about that, by the way. &lt;a href=&quot;http://gruntjs.com/&quot;&gt;Ben Alman&lt;/a&gt; created one of the most insanely useful and popular things ever, and suddenly the next thing comes along and Grunt is just &lt;em&gt;over&lt;/em&gt;. Every front-end developer I know is switching. The world moves so quickly. Grunt: you will always hold a place in my heart. You changed the way I work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough of this bland storytelling: I created my first &lt;a href=&quot;http://gulpjs.com/plugins/&quot;&gt;gulp plugin&lt;/a&gt;, recently, in response to a need we had at work to flag certain bad practices in CMS plugins. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.org/package/gulp-patternlint/&quot;&gt;Pattern Lint&lt;/a&gt; is a linter that works on any kind of file that searches the content for patterns (strings or regular expressions) and flags them, if found, outputting a custom message to your gulp process. We&amp;#39;re using it to warn people not to use &lt;code&gt;http://&lt;/code&gt; links, the wrong form of our CDN url, or vendor prefixes in their CSS file (because the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.org/package/gulp-autoprefixer&quot;&gt;autoprefixer&lt;/a&gt; plugin takes care of that).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It mostly works like other linters (I modeled it on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.org/package/gulp-csslint&quot;&gt;gulp-csslint&lt;/a&gt;), but I added an excerpting feature to the output reporter that creates an excerpt of the match along with a snippet of the contents before and after to put it into context, with the match highlighted in red. For a while, I was really into doing the JavaScript challenges on &lt;a href=&quot;http://coderbyte.com/CodingArea/Challenges/&quot;&gt;coderbyte&lt;/a&gt;, which focus a lot on string and array manipulations. It&amp;#39;s mostly stuff I already know how to do, but I found that the speed it gave me when dealing with similar problems that come up at work is really valuable. It&amp;#39;s a bit like doing tsumego to improve your reading ability in go. You work on the stuff you can solve without too much effort to increase the ease and speed with which you can do it in real life.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/sass-directory-imports-with-gulp</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/sass-directory-imports-with-gulp"/><title>Update: Sass Directory Imports With Gulp</title><updated>Thu May 22 2014 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/sass-directory-include.png&quot; class=&quot;l-full&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 674px;&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of a directory import&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like using &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/&quot;&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt; so much for writing CSS that I have really only one complaint about the language: it does not, and will not, support &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glob_%28programming%29&quot;&gt;globbing&lt;/a&gt; for its &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/documentation/file.SASS_REFERENCE.html#import&quot;&gt;@imports&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nex3&quot;&gt;Nathan Weizenbaum&lt;/a&gt;, the primary maintainer of Sass, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hcatlin/libsass/issues/156#issuecomment-34229670&quot;&gt;explains&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reference implementation of Sass doesn&amp;#39;t and will not support globbing&amp;hellip; It makes the order that rules are emitted very difficult to reason about and contingent on non-local factors. There does exist &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chriseppstein/sass-globbing&quot;&gt;a Ruby plugin&lt;/a&gt; for it, but I personally discourage its use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it&amp;#39;s not wise to speak ill of one&amp;#39;s betters, I&amp;#39;m not going to waste pixels complaining about this decision. But I use directories of certain kinds of partials as part of my CSS in a way that does not rely on order of inclusion. I have a directory for &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/documentation/file.SASS_REFERENCE.html#defining_custom_sass_functions&quot;&gt;functions&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/documentation/file.SASS_REFERENCE.html#mixins&quot;&gt;mixins&lt;/a&gt;, and one for &lt;a href=&quot;http://smacss.com/book/type-module&quot;&gt;modules&lt;/a&gt;. If any CSS from my modules affects elements outside of the container element it&amp;#39;s targeting, that&amp;#39;s a fault of mine, so order should never matter. It&amp;#39;s great that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chriseppstein/sass-globbing&quot;&gt;sass-globbing&lt;/a&gt; plugin exists, but it&amp;#39;s for Ruby. I use the much-faster &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hcatlin/libsass&quot;&gt;libsass&lt;/a&gt;, which has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/andrew/node-sass&quot;&gt;node wrapper&lt;/a&gt;, not just for the speed but also because it&amp;#39;s nice not having any dependencies for projects that aren&amp;#39;t taken care of by &lt;code&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: it&amp;#39;s at least a little bit irrational how much work I&amp;#39;m willing to put in to avoid having to list things that I already have in a directory. Whether it&amp;#39;s Angular, Express, or Sass, having to create a file and THEN tell some other file that I&amp;#39;ve added it is like nails on a blackboard for me: it&amp;#39;s just not the kind of work I feel I should have to do as a developer. I don&amp;#39;t ever want to add a module, go to my webpage, wonder why it&amp;#39;s not showing up, and realize I forgot to add it to my list of module includes. Can I justify that in terms of actual time cost? Probably not. But I don&amp;#39;t develop just to be efficient: I chose this life because it gives me pleasure to solve problems using code. And I&amp;#39;m perfectly willing to admit that I consider my own pleasure / annoyance when crafting the tools in my toolbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year ago, I &lt;a href=&quot;/2013/03/30/import-a-whole-directory-with-sass-using-grunt/&quot;&gt;wrote a simple Grunt plugin&lt;/a&gt; to make it possible to import whole directories at once by adding an &lt;code&gt;_all.scss&lt;/code&gt; file to any directory you want to import. The grunt task would find any &lt;code&gt;_all.scss&lt;/code&gt; files and write &lt;code&gt;@import&lt;/code&gt; statements to it for all the other &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/documentation/file.SASS_REFERENCE.html#partials&quot;&gt;partials&lt;/a&gt; it found in that directory. This is an idiomatic hack, but it&amp;#39;s worked really well for me, allowing me to forget that it exists while I develop projects, adding partials to my &lt;code&gt;modules&lt;/code&gt; directory as I need them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I recently &lt;a href=&quot;/2014/05/08/gulp-pattern-lint/&quot;&gt;switched to Gulp&lt;/a&gt;, so I needed a new solution. I considered writing a gulp plugin, but with Gulp&amp;#39;s emphasis on just being JavaScript, I realized that it&amp;#39;d probably be trivially simple to just use some JS inside a Gulp task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;hljs undefined&quot;&gt;var gulp = require('gulp');
// We'll use the filesystem, path, and glob packages
var fs = require('fs');
var path = require('path');
var glob = require('glob');

...

// Hack the ability to import directories in Sass
// Find any _all.scss files and write @import statements
// for all other *.scss files in the same directory
//
// Import the whole directory with @import &quot;somedir/all&quot;;
gulp.task('sass-includes', function (callback) {
    var all = '_all.scss';
    glob('./client/src/scss/**/' + all, function (error, files) {
        files.forEach(function (allFile) {
            // Add a banner to warn users
            fs.writeFileSync(allFile, '/** This is a dynamically generated file **/\n\n');

            var directory = path.dirname(allFile);
            var partials = fs.readdirSync(directory).filter(function (file) {
                return (
                    // Exclude the dynamically generated file
                    file !== all &amp;&amp;
                    // Only include _*.scss files
                    path.basename(file).substring(0, 1) === '_' &amp;&amp;
                    path.extname(file) === '.scss'
                );
            });

            // Append import statements for each partial
            partials.forEach(function (partial) {
                fs.appendFileSync(allFile, '@import &quot;' + partial + '&quot;;\n');
            });
        });
    });

    callback();
});&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is inside &lt;code&gt;Gulpfile.js&lt;/code&gt; in my project root. It accepts a callback and calls it when finished &lt;a href=&quot;http://cameronspear.com/blog/handling-sync-tasks-with-gulp-js/&quot;&gt;to make the task synchronous&lt;/a&gt;. (So that other tasks can list it as a dependency and depend on it being completed before they execute.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;hljs undefined&quot;&gt;gulp.task('sass', ['sass-includes'], function () {&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The only other thing I had to account for was the &lt;code&gt;watch&lt;/code&gt; task: I didn&amp;#39;t want it to get stuck in an infinite loop when it wrote to an &lt;code&gt;*.scss&lt;/code&gt; file in response to changes to an &lt;code&gt;*.scss&lt;/code&gt; file. So I just excluded &lt;code&gt;_all&lt;/code&gt; in the glob that triggered my &lt;code&gt;sass&lt;/code&gt; task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;hljs undefined&quot;&gt;gulp.watch('client/src/scss/**/!(_all).scss', ['sass']);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;After that, I added &lt;code&gt;_all.scss&lt;/code&gt; files to the three directories I wanted to be able to import, and including directories was as easy as this again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;hljs undefined&quot;&gt;@import &quot;functions/all&quot;;
@import &quot;mixins/all&quot;;
@import &quot;rules/modules/all&quot;;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;A final note: this isn&amp;#39;t exactly the most Gulpy way of doing things. I&amp;#39;m modifying source files rather than dealing with my Sass files as a stream, modifying them, and passing them on through a pipe to the next process. But since Sass doesn&amp;#39;t just deal with the files in the stream, it grabs imported files from outside the stream, I can&amp;#39;t just find &lt;code&gt;@import&lt;/code&gt;s in the stream and expand them myself, because it wouldn&amp;#39;t work on any imported files. But ideally, we&amp;#39;d have a nice &lt;code&gt;gulp-sass-glob&lt;/code&gt; plugin that worked that way.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/progress-updates</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/progress-updates"/><title>Progress Updates</title><updated>Thu May 29 2014 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/gokibitz-preview.gif&quot; class=&quot;l-full&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 1195px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been getting a lot done on GoKibitz (goKibitz? gokibitz? Go Kibitz?) recently. You can see a preview of the move commenting feature above. That&amp;#39;s the whole reason I started doing this, really -- I wanted to be able to have comments and discussions on individual moves in game records. There&amp;#39;s still tons of work to be done in terms of design (I&amp;#39;m using unmodified Bootstrap right now), but I&amp;#39;m pretty encouraged to have a working prototype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/waltheri/wgo.js&quot;&gt;WGo&lt;/a&gt; is also getting prettier. Jan Prokop, WGo&amp;#39;s creator, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/waltheri/wgo.js/commit/d2e6d62618f191459f0f9a401b18078b2fd0e664&quot;&gt;just added&lt;/a&gt; blurred shadows and improved stone rendering (including beautiful clamshell lines for white stones), and I &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/waltheri/wgo.js/commit/8c2b478586229ede9b6d4a7fd909c0b8c6350355&quot;&gt;added in&lt;/a&gt; resolution-doubling for Retina displays, so it doesn&amp;#39;t look fuzzy anymore on my Macbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m learning tons about &lt;a href=&quot;https://angularjs.org/&quot;&gt;Angular&lt;/a&gt; as I do this, and I&amp;#39;m happy to say I&amp;#39;m getting to the point where it&amp;#39;s at least as fun as it is consternating. Making my first custom directive, especially, was as satisfying as my first jQuery plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But progress continues: it feels good to have five weeks of productivity going on this. It feels like it&amp;#39;s getting easier, the longer the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/281626/jerry-seinfelds-productivity-secret&quot;&gt;chain&lt;/a&gt; gets.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/life-and-death-problem-and-game-record-from-yuan-zhous-monthly-group-go-lesson</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/life-and-death-problem-and-game-record-from-yuan-zhous-monthly-group-go-lesson"/><title>Life and Death Problem and Game Record from Yuan Zhou's Monthly Group Go Lesson</title><updated>Tue Jun 24 2014 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At our monthly go lessons, &lt;a href=&quot;http://zhouyuan.com/&quot;&gt;Shifu&lt;/a&gt; has a problem set out on the board in the front of the room when we walk in. We have a lot of time to try to solve it: it&amp;#39;s embarrassing how infrequently I manage to do so correctly. Even this month, with an easier-than-usual problem, I failed to get 100% of the correct result. The challenge is always to tell Shifu &amp;quot;what is the best result?&amp;quot;, not simply to find a way to achieve a stated outcome. Frequently, the best result is not simply life or death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;black-to-play&quot;&gt;Black to Play&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eidogo-player-problem&quot; sgf=&quot;/sgf/2014_06_22_problem.sgf&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Note: Eidogo&amp;#39;s problem interface is not the best. Soon I&amp;#39;ll use GoKibitz to do this, and it&amp;#39;ll work the way I want, damn it. SOON!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;nathan-returns&quot;&gt;Nathan Returns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After several months away, my nemesis Nathan returned, who is now officially 1d AGA! It&amp;#39;s some slight consolation for the fact that I&amp;#39;ve fallen behind him in our head-to-head record. This month, true to form, we had an exciting game. The game record has full commentary by Shifu Yuan Zhou, which comes courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://usgo.org&quot;&gt;the AGA&lt;/a&gt;, who paid for it, and Bill Cobb, who provides the significant work of transcribing and crafting a written record from a complex, in-person back and forth that he records on a video camera. I&amp;#39;m very grateful to Bill for that service; it&amp;#39;s no small luxury to have such a high-quality version of a strong player&amp;#39;s analysis of my games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I played black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2014_06_22_xxx_kyu-dan_yuanzhou.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eidogo-player-auto&quot; sgf=&quot;/sgf/2014_06_22_xxx_kyu-dan_yuanzhou.sgf&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a heart-breaking result to lose after working so hard to put myself in a winning position, but Nathan&amp;#39;s ability to struggle and make chances for himself is no joke. As always, my judgment is a little stronger than my reading accuracy, which makes reading--especially under time pressure--a painful weakness.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/dont-break-the-problem-chain</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/dont-break-the-problem-chain"/><title>Don't Break the Problem Chain</title><updated>Tue Aug 26 2014 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/problem-chain.jpg&quot; class=&quot;l-full&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 500px;&quot; alt=&quot;Paperclips as a Problem Chain&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone who plays go is limited by their ability to read (or calculate, as Cho Chikun puts it), or acurately foresee the future results of a potential move. Go is a game about thinking, and if you can think through the consequences of a move more accurately than your opponent you will win. (Of course, go is a famously big game, in that it&amp;#39;s very difficult to read the tree of possibilities from any given point exhaustively, which means that one relies on a tremendous amount of shape knowledge, established patterns, and even intuition to apply one&amp;#39;s reading efforts to the most useful things.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But my reading ability is one of my weakest points. Since I&amp;#39;ve taken lessons for about three years, now, I have a lot of knowledge about positional judgment, opening strategy, and other broad concepts. Against players a little bit weaker, this can be an overwhelming advantage. But the players I&amp;#39;m facing these days (3k - 1d) aren&amp;#39;t fragile enough to give games away very often, and will fight aggressively and persistently in ways that push the game into complicated fighting that requires accurate reading. And in those situations, where it really matters, I frequently give games away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a many-month losing streak going against Nathan, a 1d fellow student of &lt;a href=&quot;http://zhouyuan.com&quot;&gt;Yuan Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, and I barely managed an even &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usgo.org/tournaments/crosstab/band-matrix/169&quot;&gt;3-3 result at the US Go Congress&lt;/a&gt; (I was down 1-3 as of Thursday).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m determined to do something about this relative weakness by doing go problems every single day. I&amp;#39;ve begun a go problem chain, based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/281626/jerry-seinfelds-productivity-secret&quot;&gt;Jerry Seinfeld&amp;#39;s chain concept&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Seinfeld] told me to get a big wall calendar that has a whole year on one page and hang it on a prominent wall. The next step was to get a big red magic marker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said for each day that I do my task of writing, I get to put a big red X over that day. &amp;quot;After a few days you&amp;#39;ll have a chain. Just keep at it and the chain will grow longer every day. You&amp;#39;ll like seeing that chain, especially when you get a few weeks under your belt. Your only job next is to not break the chain.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Don&amp;#39;t break the chain,&amp;quot; he said again for emphasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m mixing things up slightly: instead of a wall calendar, I&amp;#39;ve got a set of black and white paperclips. For every day that I work on go problems, I add a paperclip to the chain. If I miss a day, I have to take the chain apart and start over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of today, I have five paperclips, and it&amp;#39;s been an effective incentive so far. Both Saturday and Monday I found myself near the end of the day, ready to collapse onto a couch and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hulu.com/grid/dragon-ball?categories=subtitled&quot;&gt;watch some Dragonball&lt;/a&gt;, but the thought of dismantling the chain really bothered me. Missing a day meant taking apart each of those paperclips and starting over. And that was hard enough to face that I made some time. I didn&amp;#39;t do a lot of problems, but I did some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;#39;s the idea. I have a lot of room to grow in terms of how many problems I do - I&amp;#39;m averaging maybe 6 - 20 problems a day right now, of varying nature and difficulty. But the biggest goal is to establish the habit firmly, and worry about refinement later. Here&amp;#39;s hoping that the coming year will see me grow toward 1k/1d as I gradually strengthen the weakest part of my game.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/planet-b-boy</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/planet-b-boy"/><title>Planet B-Boy</title><updated>Fri Sep 26 2014 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When go players talk to each other, we often ask each other how we got into go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common vector is chess: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Lasker&quot;&gt;Edward Lasker&lt;/a&gt;, a German International Master in chess, was a vital early exponent of Go in the West. Another common vector is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hulu.com/hikaru-no-go&quot;&gt;Hikaru no Go&lt;/a&gt;, an astonishingly good manga/anime that &lt;a href=&quot;http://senseis.xmp.net/?HikaruNoGo&quot;&gt;Joey Hung 8d estimated&lt;/a&gt; may have tripled the world go population. Both of these were important for me, too. My childhood desire to play chess (I learned the rules, but never any strategy) primed me to be interested in go, and it was when my friend Michael Sullivan got me to watch &lt;em&gt;Hikaru no Go&lt;/em&gt; on Hulu that I finally decided to learn to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the biggest reason I decided to play go seriously was a movie I saw accidentally, just because a couple friends invited us along to see it. The movie was one I&amp;#39;d never heard of: it was a documentary about breakdancing called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0770796/&quot;&gt;Planet B-Boy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/PpntYFfVoQU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main association with breakdancing was the guy who carried a ghetto blaster around on Sesame Street in the &amp;#39;80s, but I probably only lasted a minute or two of that movie before falling in love. The way they film b-boying (as it&amp;#39;s properly called) in &lt;em&gt;Planet B-Boy&lt;/em&gt; is one of the most exciting things I&amp;#39;d ever seen, and I was quickly swept up in the loose arc of the documentary, which is about the various teams heading to the Battle of the Year. B-boying is astoundingly physical, a combination of gymnastic prowess with the artistry of dancing; it&amp;#39;s also intensely personal, with emphasis on expressiveness and individual style. Even if you don&amp;#39;t get what&amp;#39;s appealing about b-boying right away, you&amp;#39;ll get what&amp;#39;s impressive about it immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the moments toward the end of &lt;em&gt;Planet B-Boy&lt;/em&gt; rival &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bartleby.com/122/34.html&quot;&gt;Hopkins&lt;/a&gt; (&amp;quot;Selves--goes itself; myself it speaks and spells / Crying What I do is me: for that I came&amp;quot;) or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0082158/&quot;&gt;Chariots of Fire&lt;/a&gt; in conveying the beauty of pouring one&amp;#39;s whole self into doing something. I was moved: moved and envious. What did I have in my life that I could do so fully or so beautifully?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/akira.png&quot; class=&quot;l-full&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 661px;&quot; alt=&quot;Akira's scary look&quot;&gt;
That feeling and that longing stuck with me. In &lt;em&gt;Hikaru no Go&lt;/em&gt;, when Hikaru is both frightened and fascinated by the look in Akira&amp;#39;s eyes as Akira hunts him down, desperate for a second match, I saw a chance to find something I could pour myself into as passionately as the competitors in &lt;em&gt;Planet B-Boy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s why I play go.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/gokibitz-embeds</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/gokibitz-embeds"/><title>GoKibitz Embeds</title><updated>Sat Jan 17 2015 00:00:00 GMT-0500 (EST)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yo, dudes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe id=&quot;gokibitz-Qy_2Ab4E&quot; src=&quot;http://gokibitz.com/kifu/Qy_2Ab4E&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; min-height: 500px; display: block; border: 10px solid snow;&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;script src=&quot;http://gokibitz.com/embed/Qy_2Ab4E&quot;&gt; &lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/it-is-fortunate-that-the-satisfaction-of-go...</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/it-is-fortunate-that-the-satisfaction-of-go..."/><title>It is fortunate that the satisfaction of go...</title><updated>Mon Aug 08 2016 01:00:00 GMT-0400 (EDT)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;(Written after the 2016 US Go Congress in Boston.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is fortunate that the satisfaction of go&lt;br&gt;is not reliant on victory.&lt;br&gt;How horrible and how vain&lt;br&gt;if only half of go were glorious&lt;br&gt;as if only the rich and comfortable&lt;br&gt;and powerful and triumphant&lt;br&gt;could call their lives lived.&lt;br&gt;It is better that when a go game&lt;br&gt;is left soaked in blood&lt;br&gt;or tangled in novel intricacies,&lt;br&gt;with every twist speaking its own&lt;br&gt;furious desire to fight&lt;br&gt;or delicate preservation of balance,&lt;br&gt;the landscape that it leaves,&lt;br&gt;unique and ephemeral,&lt;br&gt;affirms the deep worth&lt;br&gt;of white and black together.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is easiest to imagine peace in death&lt;br&gt;if it came during a game of go.&lt;br&gt;How effortless to say,&lt;br&gt;in standing up at last,&lt;br&gt;that this life was lived well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/unblocking-uglifyjs-so-my-spinner-could-spin</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/unblocking-uglifyjs-so-my-spinner-could-spin"/><title>Unblocking UglifyJS so my spinner could spin</title><updated>Wed Nov 23 2016 00:00:00 GMT-0500 (EST)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html"></content></entry><entry><id>http://nateeagle.com/how-i-finally-lost-weight-in-2016</id><link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://nateeagle.com/how-i-finally-lost-weight-in-2016"/><title>How I Finally Lost Weight in 2016</title><updated>Thu Jan 12 2017 00:00:00 GMT-0500 (EST)</updated><author><name>Nate Eagle</name><uri>http://nateeagle.com/</uri></author><content type="html">&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;hljs javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; foo = &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;'bar'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-function&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-title&quot;&gt;greet&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-params&quot;&gt;you&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;/span&gt;{
    alert(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;`Hello, &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-subst&quot;&gt;${you}&lt;/span&gt;!`&lt;/span&gt;)
}
greet(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;'Nate'&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is me in December of 2015. I weighed about 215 lbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/nate-before.jpg&quot; class=&quot;l-full&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 2048px;&quot; alt=&quot;Me in December of 2015 with my family&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is me in October of 2016. I weighed about 185 lbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/nate-after.jpg&quot; class=&quot;l-full&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 1365;&quot; alt=&quot;Me in October of 2016 with my family&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last time I was fit was in the aughts. I was lifting weights regularly on a rack / barbell combo my friend and I bought and kept at my house. I got rid of most sugar, bread, and other flour products in my diet and lost weight; I was somewhere around 180 lbs. My bench press took off during that period. It had always been one of my favorite lifts, and while lifting 2 - 3 times a week, my 1 RM (rep max... the highest weight you can push/pull one time) surged upward. I kept pushing, and kept testing my 1 RM. The last one I successfully lifted was 335 lbs, which is pretty decent. (What&amp;#39;s not so impressive is that I couldn&amp;#39;t &lt;em&gt;squat&lt;/em&gt; the same amount.) On the day I tried to lift 340 lbs, I felt something snap and rolled out from under the bar: I had torn over half of my right pectoral tendon away from the muscle. Muscles can grow faster than tendons can adapt. I pushed too hard, too fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, I had to physical therapy to regain range of motion, and I fell out of regular lifting. My enthusiasm and confidence were gone. My diet didn&amp;#39;t change right away, but the habits started to slip, and that began a long, slow period of progressive weight gain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weight gain period isn&amp;#39;t particularly interesting, except to note that I spent most of it &lt;em&gt;trying&lt;/em&gt; to lose weight. A lot of the food I ate was healthy: I&amp;#39;d periodically add whey protein shakes back into my diet and focus on salad-bar lunches. But it was periodic, and I&amp;#39;d make plenty of exceptions for food I loved, like burgers. I&amp;#39;d make decisions to focus on weighing myself every day and eating at a caloric deficit, but inevitably the second or third or fourth day would lead to an erasure of any weight I&amp;#39;d lost due to what I&amp;#39;d perceived as a normal day, I&amp;#39;d get frustrated, and abandon the whole thing. I lost any belief that I was capable of changing my diet enough to lose weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent about ten months when I was at AOL doing a circuit training class two times a week, where we rotated through a set of different exercises, led by a trainer, not resting much in between each station. The idea was to keep your heart rate up the whole time and get a cardio workout in addition to the weightlifting. I left every session drenched and exhausted. I didn&amp;#39;t lose any weight, and it was hard to say if I got any stronger. The trainer periodically measured our body fat percentage using a bioimpedance device, and it showed me making no progress. As a solution, my trainer dispensed juice-cleanse kits. I hope I don&amp;#39;t need to tell you that juice cleanses are bullshit. I had an small argument with him about the fact that toxins don&amp;#39;t exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;return-to-lifting&quot;&gt;Return to Lifting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, I started a new job, and I found that one of the developers who worked there went, three times a week, to lift weights at the nearby Gold&amp;#39;s Gym. I checked out the Gold&amp;#39;s, and found that they offered a month-to-month membership, so I signed up and snuck over to start trying to lift. On the second or third outing, my coworker messaged me on Slack when I got back. &amp;quot;How did you like Gold&amp;#39;s?&amp;quot; I was embarrassed he&amp;#39;d spotted me, but he invited me to lift with him, and pretty soon we&amp;#39;d settled into a routine. He was also a believer in emphasizing the core, compound barbell lifts: squat, deadlift, bench press, overhead press. We started doing the &lt;a href=&quot;http://startingstrength.com/&quot;&gt;Starting Strength&lt;/a&gt; program by Mark Rippetoe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best thing about my coworker was his diligence: it just wasn&amp;#39;t ever a question whether we&amp;#39;d workout. We just did it, rain or shine, whatever else was going on. And I started getting stronger and stronger. My squat and deadlift weights, especially, shot up, even though my bench press was stuck pretty low. (And probably will be forever, due to the pec injury.) I also switched to eating as few carbs as possible. Salads with meat instead of meals with rice, nothing with bread, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to notice changes pretty soon, as the muscles in my shoulders and arms got more visible. I started wearing t-shirts by themselves, without always wearing a long-sleeved shirt over them to cover up body parts I felt made me look fat. To some degree, I was &amp;quot;recomping&amp;quot;, or altering the composition of my body as I lost some fat and gained some muscle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By July, I was strong enough that I tested my 1 RMs for deadlift, squat, and bench press, and managed to total more than 1000 lbs, which is a decent milestone for a man. But though my weight had gone down to 205 for a while when I started lifting, it was back up to 217. I didn&amp;#39;t want to stay strong but fat, so I decided to get serious about cutting, or running a calorie deficit, to reduce the amount of body fat I had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The general word on cutting is that it&amp;#39;s hard or impossible to gain muscle at the same time, so you usually choose between whether you&amp;#39;re going to get stronger or leaner. There&amp;#39;s some wiggle room there, especially if you still have a lot of body fat, which I did. Everyone has their own goals, and a lot of men think it&amp;#39;s better to keep working on getting bigger and stronger, and stop vainly worrying about abs. For me, though, one of the biggest reasons I wanted to get fit was that my self-consciousness about how I looked without a shirt on had kept me from enjoying activities involving swimming for years. I felt miserable during vacations at the beach and let my wife take our son to swimming lessons on her own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;anti-charity&quot;&gt;Anti-Charity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how to do it? I was pretty familiar with most of the mechanisms involving losing weight, but putting them all together, getting all the versions of me at every different time of day to sign on to the same program, had proved impossible time after time after time. I decided to try something serious: I signed on to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stickk.com&quot;&gt;stickk.com&lt;/a&gt; and created a weight-loss committment that came with a serious threat. If I didn&amp;#39;t meet my weekly goal, it would donate $10 of real money--my money--to a SuperPAC that supported the candidate I did not want to become President. (I won&amp;#39;t alienate any of you by specifying which candidate that was, so let&amp;#39;s just say that their name rhymed with Ronald Grump.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of anti-charity motivation is that the thought of your money being used for something abhorrent to you can be a more powerful motivator than other incentives. And, for me, it really worked. I knew that having my money donated to the SuperPAC was &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; an option, so I got serious. I already knew the main thing I had to do, which was eliminate eating &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; supper in the evenings. My breakfasts and lunches were already pretty locked down, but I&amp;#39;d always get a surge of calories later in the day, when I got hungry after 9 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first week went well, and then the really lucky thing happened: I went away for a week to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gocongress.org/&quot;&gt;Go Congress&lt;/a&gt; in Boston. It was a week of tournament play, workshops, and other go activities, and I left my family at home. I lived in a dorm on campus, had a meal plan, and had the most success I&amp;#39;ve ever had at sticking to a diet. I ate vegetables and proteins for each and every meal, controlled my portions, and because I was constantly thinking about go during the day, never thought about being hungry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also discovered a benefit to the anti-charity goal that I hadn&amp;#39;t anticipated. It&amp;#39;s hard, when you&amp;#39;re eating a bunch of salads around other people, to avoid having one&amp;#39;s choices noticed and commented on. Nobody means to be mean about it, but it comes up, and then you end up having to defend why you&amp;#39;re trying to lose weight, and it&amp;#39;s awkward. But I found that if I just briefly told people that I was losing weight because I sure as hell wasn&amp;#39;t going to donate money to Ronald Grump, their reaction changed from &amp;quot;you don&amp;#39;t need to lose weight&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;um, I think you&amp;#39;ve had enough tomatoes.&amp;quot; And that was great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;consistency&quot;&gt;Consistency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a way, that&amp;#39;s the end of the story. When you maintain a consistent caloric deficit over a long period of time, your weight slowly goes down. I&amp;#39;ve maintained a lot of my strength, though I haven&amp;#39;t &lt;em&gt;gained&lt;/em&gt; much, either. I went down, pound by pound, over the course of months, and I gradually saw fat disappear and get replaced by visible muscles and veins. And that felt great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What that doesn&amp;#39;t tell you, of course, is what it&amp;#39;s like during that period. It &lt;em&gt;doesn&amp;#39;t&lt;/em&gt; involve feeling hungry all the time, though it definitely involved learning to feel a little hungry &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of the time. I had to learn to lean in to the feeling of being a little hungry when I went to sleep. If I didn&amp;#39;t feel a little hungry, I usually hadn&amp;#39;t run a deficit, and I had to eat a little less the following day. But eating a 100-calorie snack before bed was often useful, and going to bed &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; hungry wasn&amp;#39;t smart, because famished-Nate would wake up during the night and eat something, diet be damned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly, my habits did the work of food selection for me. That, and Blue Apron. We started doing two-person Blue Apron meals, which were shockingly tasty, and reasonably portioned. If there wasn&amp;#39;t enough food to have leftovers, I didn&amp;#39;t overeat. But if there _is_ enough food for leftovers, I&amp;#39;m kinda screwed, because it&amp;#39;s very hard for me to stop eating something delicious while there&amp;#39;s still a bunch in a dish in the middle of the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also, of course, &lt;em&gt;constantly&lt;/em&gt; thought about food, exercise, fitness, and my own body. And while that&amp;#39;s not exactly misery, it takes a ton of mental energy and attention. I started reading a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;https://reddit.com/r/fitness&quot;&gt;/r/fitness&lt;/a&gt;, and did a lot of other reading on weightlifting. I had to keep my mind busy, thinking about my goals, learning more about eating and lifting. It&amp;#39;s not trivial to lose weight. Even though the principles are relatively simple, the sustained focus it requires isn&amp;#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;takeaways&quot;&gt;Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here are some takeaways, mostly for my own benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-don-t-have-to-do-cardio-to-lose-weight-&quot;&gt;You don&amp;#39;t have to do cardio to lose weight.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate extended cardio. I&amp;#39;m not saying you have to hate cardio, or that it&amp;#39;s not beneficial. But it&amp;#39;s not really the best thing for losing weight, since it doesn&amp;#39;t really burn that many calories. All I do is five minutes of walking at 4 MPH at an incline (10 - 14%) before I work out, mostly to get my body temperature up. Cardio can have all sorts of benefits, but if it&amp;#39;s one of the main ways you&amp;#39;re trying to create a calorie deficit, I think it&amp;#39;s dangerous. Because it&amp;#39;s exhausting, and if you don&amp;#39;t &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; it, and you eventually stop doing it as much or as intensely, your weight loss will stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-cannot-depend-on-willpower-&quot;&gt;You cannot depend on willpower.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#39;t lose weight by using your willpower. Our willpower sucks. We have a limited supply of it, and if you use it on not eating, even if you&amp;#39;re successful on a given day, you won&amp;#39;t have it for other important things like not swearing at an annoying coworker. You lose weight by creating structure and establishing habits. You eat the same thing a lot, because you know how many calories it has and you know you like it. You know you&amp;#39;re eating a salad with meat for lunch every day. You pay enough that it&amp;#39;s a good, satisfying meal. You have the same whey protein shake for breakfast every day, because you never have to think about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you don&amp;#39;t get too depressed over the parties, holidays, and inevitable breaches in discipline, because the next day you get back to the routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;accept-that-progress-will-never-feel-fast-or-inevitable-while-it-s-happening&quot;&gt;Accept that progress will never feel fast or inevitable while it&amp;#39;s happening&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, the months from July to December look like one steady, happy march toward success. But they almost never felt that way. I frequently felt on the verge of failure, or as if the progress I made was worthless since I still thought I looked horrible. I always felt so far from where I wanted to be. Those are stupid feelings, but they&amp;#39;re feelings that I never really got rid of, as much as I was able to understand that you don&amp;#39;t get to a goal without going through the intermediary steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But focusing on the rewards along the way helped a little bit. I got to buy new jeans as my waist size decreased. I bought new shirts in size large, then size medium. And I read Reddit Fitness a lot, because it had a bunch of people angstily and vainly worrying about their own weight, muscles, and progress just like I was, and it helped me feel better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;bioimpedence-sucks&quot;&gt;Bioimpedence sucks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I mentioned a bioimpedence device a little while ago. That&amp;#39;s a device, either handheld or a scale you stand on, that sends an electrical current through your body to measure body fat. Since body fat has different electrical resistance than other tissue, you can apply an algorithm to the current and estimate some stats about body composition. My bioimpedance scale told me I was about 28% BF when I started cutting in July. I was down to 22% around Thanksgiving, when I was talking with my lifting partner about what my target weight was. He told me my scale was absurd and that my BF% was lower than it indicated, and that my target weight should therefore be &lt;em&gt;higher&lt;/em&gt; than what I was saying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To settle the bet, I paid a bunch of money to do a &lt;a href=&quot;https://breakingmuscle.com/learn/the-scale-lies-why-the-dexa-scan-is-best&quot;&gt;DEXA scan&lt;/a&gt;, which is basically an X-Ray that gives much more accurate data about body composition. It found that my overall BF% was 15%, which was radically lower than my scale said. The technician didn&amp;#39;t really give me a great answer as to why my scale might be so off, but let that just be a warning to you: that level of inaccuracy might lead you to set radically incorrect goals for yourself. For me, it had me thinking I needed to target a weight around 165 lbs ultimately. The DEXA scan said I had 165 lbs of lean body mass, which means aiming for that weight would put me at 0% BF, which would have me be dead. Now I now that something between 175 - 180% will be &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; lean, and that I definitely shouldn&amp;#39;t try for anything lower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Losing weight requires living counter-culturally. It takes time and money and structure and energy. But it is possible! If you&amp;#39;re trying to lose weight, I hope some of the things I learned can help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></author></feed>